<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><xml><records><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><titles><title>Creating and Ecological Network</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Sussex Wildlife Trust_Creating an Ecological Network.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kampala Ramsar Convention</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Guidelines for the rapid assessment of inland , coastal and marine wetland biodiversity</title></titles><periodical/><pages>45</pages><issue>November 2005</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2008</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>doi:10.1117/12.631715</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://guide-rapid-e.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>An unsupervised method for plant species identification was developed which uses computer extracted individual whole leaves from color images of crop canopies. Green canopies were isolated from soil/residue backgrounds using a modified Excess Green and Excess Red separation method. Connected components of isolated green regions of interest were changed into pixel fragments using the Gustafson-Kessel fuzzy clustering method. The fragments were reassembled as individual leaves using a genetic optimization algorithm and a fitness method. Pixels of whole leaves were then analyzed using the elliptic Fourier shape and Haralick's classical textural feature analyses. A binary template was constructed to represent each selected leaf region of interest. Elliptic Fourier descriptors were generated from a chain encoding of the leaf boundary. Leaf template orientation was corrected by rotating each extracted leaf to a standard horizontal position. This was done using information provided from the first harmonic set of coefficients. Textural features were computed from the grayscale co-occurrence matrix of the leaf pixel set. Standardized leaf orientation significantly improved the leaf textural venation results. Principle component analysis from SAS® was used to select the best Fourier descriptors and textural indices. Indices of local homogeneity, and entropy were found to contribute to improved classification rates. A SAS classification model was developed and correctly classified 83% of redroot pigweed, 100% of sunflower 83% of soybean, and 73% of velvetleaf species. An overall plant species correct classification rate of 86% was attained.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Defra</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Eel Management plans for the United Kingdom - England and Wales</title></titles><periodical/><pages>38</pages><issue>March</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2010</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Defra - 2010 - Eel Management plans for the United Kingdom - England and Wales.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Acieem, Ben Wood</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Using Condatis to predict national ecological flows</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://02BenWood.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Land, R</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>South Norfolk District Ecological Network Mapping Compiled by Econet Topic Group South Norfolk District Ecological Network Mapping</title></titles><periodical/><issue>January</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2007</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://South Norfolk ecological network report 2007.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Edge, Christopher B.</author><author>Fortin, Marie Josée</author><author>Jackson, Donald A.</author><author>Lawrie, David</author><author>Stanfield, Les</author><author>Shrestha, Namrata</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Habitat alteration and habitat fragmentation differentially affect beta diversity of stream fish communities</title><secondary-title>Landscape Ecology</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Landscape Ecology</full-title></periodical><pages>647-662</pages><volume>32</volume><issue>3</issue><keywords><keyword>Agriculture</keyword><keyword>Community response</keyword><keyword>Dendritic ecological network</keyword><keyword>Freshwater fish</keyword><keyword>Meta-community</keyword><keyword>Stream fragmentation</keyword><keyword>Urbanization</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><publisher>Springer Netherlands</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1007/s10980-016-0472-9</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Edgeetal2016LandEcol.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Context The cumulative impact of broad scale environmental change includes altered land-cover and fragmentation. Both altered land-cover and fragmentation have a negative effect on species diversity, but the scale they act on may differ because land-cover alters environmental characteristics, whereas fragmentation alters movement among sites. Objectives We evaluated the scale specific effects of land-cover, fragmentation, and habitat size on alpha and beta diversity (total, turnover, and nestedness). Methods Stream fish communities were sampled across five urbanizing watersheds. Generalized mixed linear models were used to test how diversity (alpha and beta) is affected by land-cover, connectivity, and habitat size. Indices of land-cover were calculated from correspondence analyses on land-cover data, fragmentation was estimated with the dendritic connectivity index, and habitat size was calculated as the length of the stream segment (alpha diversity) or the length of the stream network (beta diversity). Results Alpha diversity was most strongly related to land-cover variables associated with urban development and agriculture (negative relationship with urbanization). Whereas, beta diversity was most strongly influenced by habitat size (positive relationship) and fragmentation (positive relationship). Turnover was positively correlated with fragmentation and habitat size, whereas species loss was negatively correlated with habitat size. Conclusions Land-cover has a larger effect on alpha diversity because it alters the environmental conditions at a site, whereas fragmentation has a larger effect on beta diversity because it affects the movement of individuals among sites. Assessing the cumulative impact of environmental change requires a multiscale approach that simultaneously considers alpha and beta diversity.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Book">1</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Defra - UK</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>The Natural Choice: securing the value of nature</title><secondary-title>English</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>English</full-title></periodical><pages>2011</pages><issue>June</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2011</year></dates><isbn>9780101808224</isbn><accession-num>25246403</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1017/CBO9781107415324.004</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://8082_TheNaturalChoice.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.official-documents.gov.uk/document/cm80/8082/8082.pdf</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>This white paper sets out proposals for a detailed programme of action to repair damage done To The environment in the past, and urges everyone to get involved in helping nature to flourish at all levels-from neighbourhoods to national parks. The plans are directly ...</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>England, West</author><author>Brookes, Naomi</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>South West Nature Map</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://southwestnaturemap.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Gautam, Parikshit</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Inventory , assessment and monitoring of wetlands : An integrated approach</title></titles><periodical/><issue>November</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2007</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://KN-7 Parikhshit Gautam.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kroon, Frederieke J.</author><author>Phillips, Seonaid</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Identification of human-made physical barriers to fish passage in the Wet Tropics region, Australia</title><secondary-title>Marine and Freshwater Research</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Marine and Freshwater Research</full-title></periodical><pages>677-681</pages><volume>67</volume><issue>5</issue><keywords><keyword>bridges</keyword><keyword>causeways</keyword><keyword>connectivity</keyword><keyword>culverts</keyword><keyword>flow regime</keyword><keyword>migration.</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1071/MF14397</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Kroon and Phillips, 2016.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Human-made physical barriers to fish passage were identified in the Wet Tropics region, Far North Queensland, Australia, through a desktop GIS analysis of the stream and transport networks. A total of 3748 of such potential barriers, comprising bridges, culverts and causeways, were identified in a stream network of 18 363 km at a scale of 1 : 100 000. These records provide a first step for a complete barrier inventory and assessment for this region, which can be used to prioritise potential barriers for removal and remediation to improve native fish movement and fisheries production. </abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><titles><title>Somerset Idb Biodiversity Action Plan</title></titles><periodical/><issue>April</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2010</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Unknown - 2010 - Somerset Idb Biodiversity Action Plan.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Eel, European</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Anguilla anguilla,</title></titles><periodical/><volume>8235</volume><keywords/><dates><year>2015</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://IUCNAnguillaAnguilla.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Manager, Upstream Thinking</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Peatland restoration on the shallow blanket mires of Exmoor: measuring the effects on ecology, farming, hydrology and climate</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><dates><year>2008</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://8._David_Smith_-_CIEEM_SW_Conf_2015.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Hodgson, Jenny A.</author><author>Wallis, David W.</author><author>Krishna, Ritesh</author><author>Cornell, Stephen J.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>How to manipulate landscapes to improve the potential for range expansion</title><secondary-title>Methods in Ecology and Evolution</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Methods in Ecology and Evolution</full-title></periodical><pages>1558-1566</pages><volume>7</volume><issue>12</issue><keywords><keyword>circuit theory</keyword><keyword>climate change</keyword><keyword>dispersal</keyword><keyword>ecological restoration</keyword><keyword>indicators</keyword><keyword>invasion</keyword><keyword>networks</keyword><keyword>optimisation</keyword><keyword>reserve design</keyword><keyword>systematic conservation planning</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><isbn>2041-210X</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/2041-210X.12614</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Hodgson et al. - 2016 - How to manipulate landscapes to improve the potential for range expansion.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>1. Climate change is a global threat to species, and their capacity to adapt could be limited by habitat fragmentation. Many initiatives to restore habitats, increase connectivity and/or ensure `functioning ecological networks' are explicitly or implicitly trying to address this threat. However, existing methods of analysing networks mainly treat the landscape as static, and it is difficult to use these to plan restoration. 2. We use a recent method to approximate the speed of a species' range expansion through a landscape by an analogy to an electrical circuit, which takes into account both the rates of colonisation between patches and the rates at which occupied habitat produces new emigrants. Based on this, we propose and test two methods that can help to optimise the spatial arrangement of habitat for range expansion. 3. First, high current flowing through a habitat patch indicates that it should be a priority for conservation, and this can be the basis of an algorithm for iteratively dropping the least valuable patches. Secondly, high power in a link between two patches indicates that it is a bottleneck in the circuit, and this can be the basis of an algorithm for iteratively adding new patches in the most efficient places. We show that these methods perform well for a variety of realistic landscape patterns, assuming known and fixed dispersal ability and source/target locations. 4. The calculations involved for each parameter set are fast enough to be used as building blocks in a larger optimisation for practical planning of landscapes for multiple species. Thus, we lay the foundation for a new genre of systematic conservation planning, which efficiently proposes restoration as well as minimising loss.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><titles><title>Prioritising habitat delivery within B-Lines B-Lines – part of the solution !</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://03ClareDinham.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Anon</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Second Report of Working Group P5: the Handling and Storage of Dry and Prepared Foundry Sands.</title><secondary-title>Br Foundryman</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Br Foundryman</full-title></periodical><pages>65-88</pages><volume>70</volume><issue>pt 3</issue><keywords/><dates><year>1977</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1007/BF02447513</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://RothLandsEcol1996streamintegrity.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>The biological integrity of stream ecosystems depends critically on human activities that affect land use/cover along stream margins and possibly throughout the catchment. We evaluated stream condition using an Index of Biotic Integrity (IBI) and a habitat index (HI), and compared these measures to landscape and riparian conditions assessed at different spatial scales in a largely agricultural Midwestern watershed. Our goal was to determine whether land use/cover was an effective predictor of stream integrity, and if so, at what spatial scale. Twenty-three sites in first-through third-order headwater streams were surveyed by electrofishing and site IBIs were calculated based on ten metrics of the fish collection. Habitat features were characterized through field observation, and site HIs calculated from nine instream and bank metrics. Field surveys, aerial photograph interpretation, and geographic information system (GIS) analyses provided assessments of forested land and other vegetation covers at the local, reach, and regional (catchment) scales. The range of conditions among the 23 sites varied from poor to very good based on IBI and KI scores, and habitat and fish assemblage measures were highly correlated. Stream biotic integrity and habitat quality were negatively correlated with the extent of agriculture and positively correlated with extent of wetlands and forest. Correlations were strongest at the catchment scale (IBI with % area as agriculture, r(2) = 0.50, HI with agriculture, r(2) = 0.76), and tended to become weak and non-significant at local scales. Local riparian vegetation was a weak secondary predictor of stream integrity. In this watershed, regional land use is the primary determinant of stream conditions, able to overwhelm the ability of local site vegetation to support high-quality habitat and biotic communities.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Feunteun, Eric</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Management and restoration of European eel population (Anguilla anguilla): An impossible bargain</title><secondary-title>Ecological Engineering</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Ecological Engineering</full-title></periodical><pages>575-591</pages><volume>18</volume><issue>5</issue><keywords><keyword>Habitat</keyword><keyword>Models</keyword><keyword>Monitoring</keyword><keyword>Population dynamics</keyword><keyword>Socio-economy</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2002</year></dates><isbn>0925-8574</isbn><accession-num>11495740</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/S0925-8574(02)00021-6</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Fetuen, 2002.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>The European eel panmicitic population has been declining at least since the 1980s throughout its distribution area. The stocks are now ten times lower than they were initially. The causes of this decline are reviewed in this paper: marine causes such as Gulf Stream shifts are thought to reduce survival of leptocephali larvae during their transoceanic migration, but inland causes are also suspected, i.e. overfishing of all continental stages, obstructions to upstream and downstream migrations, habitat loss, water quality, parasite and xenobiotic contamination, which together contribute to reducing quality and quantity of spawner escapement from European inland waters to sea. Restoration programs have been conducted in several inland hydrosystems in Europe. If local fisheries have been sustained mainly by stocking elvers and glass eels, no significant restoration of the population has been observed suggesting that restoration plans are inefficient, despite significant efforts and relevant technologies (fish passage). The causes for the failure of restoration projects are listed and discussed, and it is shown that the minimum scale to work at is the catchment area. But international cooperation is required to coordinate programs, to determine common objectives and policies. Concepts for sustainable restoration and management are provided and discussed together with the general interest of eel population as a biointegrator of the quality and integrity of inland hydrosystems. © 2002 Elsevier Science B.V. All rights reserved.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Stratford, Charlie</author><author>Acreman, Mike</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Somerset Levels and Moors: Assessment of the Impact of Water Level Management on Flood Risk</title><secondary-title>Somerset Drainage Boards Consortium</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Somerset Drainage Boards Consortium</full-title></periodical><pages>44</pages><issue>October</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2014</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Stratford, Acreman - 2014 - Somerset Levels and Moors Assessment of the Impact of Water Level Management on Flood Risk.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.somersetdrainageboards.gov.uk/media/Ditch-and-Soil-Storage-Report.pdf</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Buddendorf, Willem B.</author><author>Malcolm, Iain A.</author><author>Geris, Josie</author><author>Wilkinson, Mark E.</author><author>Soulsby, Chris</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Metrics to assess how longitudinal channel network connectivity and in-stream Atlantic salmon habitats are impacted by hydropower regulation</title><secondary-title>Hydrological Processes</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Hydrological Processes</full-title></periodical><pages>2132-2142</pages><volume>31</volume><issue>12</issue><keywords><keyword>Atlantic salmon</keyword><keyword>hydropower</keyword><keyword>longitudinal channel connectivity</keyword><keyword>river network</keyword><keyword>river regulation</keyword><keyword>weighting</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><isbn>0885-6087</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/hyp.11159</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Buddendorf et al., 2017.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Habitat fragmentation in channel networks and riverine ecosystems is increasing globally due to the construction of barriers and river regulation. The resulting divergence from the natural state poses a threat to ecosystem integrity. Consequently, a trade-off is required between the conservation of biodiversity in channel networks and socio-economic factors including power generation, potable water supplies, fisheries and tourism. Many of Scotland's rivers are regulated for hydropower generation but also support populations of Atlantic salmon (Salmo salar L.) that have high economic and conservation value. This paper investigates the use of connectivity metrics and weightings to assess the impact of river barriers (impoundments) associated with hydropower regulation on natural longitudinal channel connectivity for Atlantic salmon. We applied two different weighting approaches in the connectivity models that accounted for spatial variability in habitat quality for spawning and fry production and contrasted these models with a more traditional approach using wetted area. Assessments of habitat loss using the habitat quality weighted models contrasted with those using the less biologically relevant wetted area. This highlights the importance of including relevant ecological and hydrogeomorphic information in assessing regulation impacts on natural channel connectivity. Specifically, we highlight scenarios where losing a smaller area of productive habitat can have a larger impact on Atlantic salmon than losing a greater area of less suitable habitat. It is recommended that future channel connectivity assessments should attempt to include biologically relevant weightings, rather than relying on simpler metrics like wetted area which can produce misleading assessments of barrier impacts.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Tower, Brodie</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Liverpool Campus Map</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><isbn>9780874216561</isbn><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Tower - Unknown - Liverpool Campus Map.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Watts, K</author><author>Humphrey, J W</author><author>Griffiths, M</author><author>Quine, C</author><author>Ray, D</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>in Fragmented Landscapes : Principles SUMMARY</title><secondary-title>Forestry commission</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Forestry commission</full-title></periodical><pages>1-8</pages><keywords><keyword>Biodiversity</keyword><keyword>forests</keyword><keyword>landscape</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2005</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Watts et al. - 2005 - in Fragmented Landscapes Principles SUMMARY.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Finlayson, Max</author><author>Davidson, Nick</author><author>Fennessy, Siobhan</author><author>Coates, David</author><author>Gardner Contributing Authors, Royal C</author><author>Darwall, Will</author><author>Dema, Michael</author><author>Everard, Mark</author><author>McRae, Louise</author><author>Perennou, Christian</author><author>Stroud, David</author><author>Bambaradeniya, Channa</author><author>Davies, Peter</author><author>Fang, Wei-Ta</author><author>Hilomen, Vincent</author><author>Kulindwa, Kassim</author><author>Martinez, Laura</author><author>Ricaurte, Luisa</author><author>Scoullos, Michael</author><author>de Silva, Sanjiv</author><author>Michael Steiner Section, Gert</author><author>Authors, Lead</author><author>Gardner, Royal C</author><author>Baker, Chris</author><author>Kumar, Ritesh</author><author>Stroud Contributing Authors, David</author><author>Barchiesi, Stefano</author><author>Max Finlayson, C</author><author>Okuno, Erin</author><author>Perennou Editor, Christian</author><author>Dudley, Nigel</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Citation: Ramsar Convention on Wetlands</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><dates><year>2018</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Finlayson et al. - 2018 - Citation Ramsar Convention on Wetlands.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>cover pic to show natural wetland with human flourishing GLOBAL WETLAND OUTLOOK State of the world's wetlands and their services to people 2018 Convention on Wetlands</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Miranda, Rafael</author><author>Copp, Gordon H.</author><author>Williams, James</author><author>Beyer, Kathleen</author><author>Gozlan, Rodolphe E.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Do Eurasian otters &amp;lt;I&amp;gt;Lutra lutra&amp;lt;/I&amp;gt; (L.) in the Somerset Levels prey preferentially on non-native fish species?</title><secondary-title>Fundamental and Applied Limnology / Archiv für Hydrobiologie</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Fundamental and Applied Limnology / Archiv für Hydrobiologie</full-title></periodical><pages>339-347</pages><volume>172</volume><issue>4</issue><keywords><keyword>alien species</keyword><keyword>angling amen-</keyword><keyword>biological resistance</keyword><keyword>conservation</keyword><keyword>cyprinids</keyword><keyword>dietary electivities</keyword><keyword>dispersal</keyword><keyword>food preferences</keyword><keyword>ity</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2008</year></dates><isbn>1863-9135</isbn><accession-num>91</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1127/1863-9135/2008/0172-0339</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Miranda et al. - 2008 - Do Eurasian otters &amp;ltI&amp;gtLutra lutra&amp;ltI&amp;gt (L.) in the Somerset Levels prey preferentially on non-native fish.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://openurl.ingenta.com/content/xref?genre=article&amp;issn=1863-9135&amp;volume=172&amp;issue=4&amp;spage=339</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Eurasian otters Lutra lutra (L.) are known to be opportunistic, exploiting the most abundant prey available, however, there have been few studies of otter diet in lowland areas of Britain. The Somerset Levels and Moors, a coastal flood plain and marsh area of 64 000 ha in SW England, is an otter stronghold where a number of introduced, non-native fishes (common carp Cyprinus carpio, pumpkinseed Lepomis gibbosus, sunbleak Leucaspius delineatus) have been introduced, with the latter species occurring locally in high abundances. The present study aimed to determine whether otters of the Somerset Levels are preying on, and thus represent `biological resistance' to, these non-native fishes. In 2004-2005, otter spraints (feces) were collected seasonally in areas of the Levels also subjected to fisheries surveys, and the data were used to determine diet composition and preferences. Otter diet was dominated by European eel Anguilla anguilla and threespine stickleback Gasterosteus aculeatus, and non-native species occurred relatively rarely (carp, sunbleak) or not at all (pumpkinseed) in the otter spraints. Seasonal variations in otter diet were observed, with birds notable for summer and sticklebacks for winter. Despite their relative prominence in the Somerset Levels, non-native fish species represented minor components of the otter's diet, a pattern also observed in Spain. In particular, the popular angling species (carp) was taken infrequently, but the species of high conservation interest (eel) was a preferred and common item in otter diet.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Generic">31</ref-type><titles><title>2018_08_15 08-44-43.pdf</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://2018_08_15 08-44-43.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Book">1</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Gordon, Nancy D</author><author>McMahon, Thomas A</author><author>Finlayson, Brian L</author><author>Gippel, Christopher J</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Stream hydrology: an introduction for ecologists</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><dates><year>2004</year></dates><publisher>John Wiley and Sons</publisher><isbn>0470843578</isbn><urls/></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Buddendorf, Willem B.</author><author>Malcolm, Iain A.</author><author>Geris, Josie</author><author>Wilkinson, Mark E.</author><author>Soulsby, Chris</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Metrics to assess how longitudinal channel network connectivity and in-stream Atlantic salmon habitats are impacted by hydropower regulation</title><secondary-title>Hydrological Processes</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Hydrological Processes</full-title></periodical><pages>2132-2142</pages><volume>31</volume><issue>12</issue><keywords><keyword>Atlantic salmon</keyword><keyword>hydropower</keyword><keyword>longitudinal channel connectivity</keyword><keyword>river network</keyword><keyword>river regulation</keyword><keyword>weighting</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2017</year></dates><isbn>0885-6087</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/hyp.11159</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Buddendorf et al., 2017.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Habitat fragmentation in channel networks and riverine ecosystems is increasing globally due to the construction of barriers and river regulation. The resulting divergence from the natural state poses a threat to ecosystem integrity. Consequently, a trade-off is required between the conservation of biodiversity in channel networks and socio-economic factors including power generation, potable water supplies, fisheries and tourism. Many of Scotland's rivers are regulated for hydropower generation but also support populations of Atlantic salmon (Salmo salar L.) that have high economic and conservation value. This paper investigates the use of connectivity metrics and weightings to assess the impact of river barriers (impoundments) associated with hydropower regulation on natural longitudinal channel connectivity for Atlantic salmon. We applied two different weighting approaches in the connectivity models that accounted for spatial variability in habitat quality for spawning and fry production and contrasted these models with a more traditional approach using wetted area. Assessments of habitat loss using the habitat quality weighted models contrasted with those using the less biologically relevant wetted area. This highlights the importance of including relevant ecological and hydrogeomorphic information in assessing regulation impacts on natural channel connectivity. Specifically, we highlight scenarios where losing a smaller area of productive habitat can have a larger impact on Atlantic salmon than losing a greater area of less suitable habitat. It is recommended that future channel connectivity assessments should attempt to include biologically relevant weightings, rather than relying on simpler metrics like wetted area which can produce misleading assessments of barrier impacts.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Canning, Paul</author><author>Samphier, Richard</author><author>Mice, Ceng</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Intelligent water level management within the Somerset Levels and Moors INTELLIGENT WATER LEVEL MANAGEMENT WITHIN THE SOMERSET LEVELS AND MOORS</title></titles><periodical/><issue>April</issue><keywords><keyword>model predictive control</keyword><keyword>river flooding</keyword><keyword>water level management</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://OLSCSpaperfinal_EnvironmentAgency_WaterControlSomerset.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><titles><title>Fens Biodiversity Audit</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://5fensbiodiversityauditfinalreport24-10-2012.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Aprahamian, M. W.</author><author>Walker, A. M.</author><author>Williams, B.</author><author>Bark, A.</author><author>Knights, B.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>On the application of models of European eel (Anguilla anguilla) production and escapement to the development of Eel Management Plans: The River Severn</title><secondary-title>ICES Journal of Marine Science</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ICES Journal of Marine Science</full-title></periodical><pages>1472-1482</pages><volume>64</volume><issue>7</issue><keywords><keyword>Anguilla anguilla</keyword><keyword>Catchment</keyword><keyword>Escapement</keyword><keyword>Model</keyword><keyword>Population</keyword><keyword>Silver eel</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2007</year></dates><isbn>1054-3139</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1093/icesjms/fsm131</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Aprahamian et al., .pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>The European eel stock has declined significantly since the 1980s, and the Eel Recovery Plan of the European Commission requires Member States to develop river basin Eel Management Plans (EMPs) that will achieve an escapement of silver eels that equals or exceeds 40% of the escapement biomass that would be produced in the absence of human activities. However, because silver eel esca- pement is not quantified within the UK, a modelling approach is required to estimate potential and actual escapement, and to assess the likely effects of management measures. We focus on two approaches developed in the UK, the Reference Condition Model (RCM) and the Scenario-based Model for Eel Populations (SMEP), and illustrate how such approaches can be used in EMPs using selected data from the River Severn. The RCM results indicate that the yellow eel population in the River Severn basin may be just 30–40% of the potential density indicated by reference conditions derived from a selection of rivers between the late 1970s and the early 1980s. The challenges of applying a model designed to be as realistic of eel production as possible, and the limited data on natural eel habitat and eel production in the Severn, preclude a SMEP analysis similar to that of the RCM, but simulations based on a simplified basin description and eel survey data from the early 1980s illustrate the potential of this model to assess compliance and test management scenarios. Keywords:</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Project, Nerc-funded Innovation</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Decision support for restoring ecological connectivity in rapidly developing , biodiverse countries</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://01LydiaCole.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kent, Mapping B-lines</author><author>Evans, Paul</author><author>Lane, Ham</author><author>Waterville, Orton</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>‘ Making a B-Line for Kent and Sussex ’</title></titles><periodical/><issue>4132695</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2015</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Kent et al. - 2015 - ‘ Making a B-Line for Kent and Sussex ’.pdf</url><url>internal-pdf://Kent et al. - 2015 - ‘ Making a B-Line for Kent and Sussex ’(2).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Generic">31</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Felix, Aliny</author><author>Rosa, Edson</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>a Gestão Documental Como Suporte Ao Governo Eletrônico : Caso Da Secretaria De Estado Da Saúde De Santa Catarina ( Ses / Sc )</title></titles><periodical/><pages>36-50</pages><keywords/><isbn>9781627480031</isbn><accession-num>17504609</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1561/2200000016</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Daverat et al., 2006.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Neeson, Thomas M</author><author>Ferris, Michael C</author><author>Diebel, Matthew W</author><author>Doran, Patrick J</author><author>Hanley, Jesse R O</author><author>Mcintyre, Peter B</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Enhancing ecosystem restoration efficiency through spatial and temporal coordination</title></titles><periodical/><pages>1-6</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2015</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1073/pnas.1423812112</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Neeson et al., 2014.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Aprahamian, M. W.</author><author>Walker, A. M.</author><author>Williams, B.</author><author>Bark, A.</author><author>Knights, B.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>On the application of models of European eel (Anguilla anguilla) production and escapement to the development of Eel Management Plans: The River Severn</title><secondary-title>ICES Journal of Marine Science</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>ICES Journal of Marine Science</full-title></periodical><pages>1472-1482</pages><volume>64</volume><issue>7</issue><keywords><keyword>Anguilla anguilla</keyword><keyword>Catchment</keyword><keyword>Escapement</keyword><keyword>Model</keyword><keyword>Population</keyword><keyword>Silver eel</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2007</year></dates><isbn>1054-3139</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1093/icesjms/fsm131</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Aprahamian et al. - 2007 - On the application of models of European eel (Anguilla anguilla) production and escapement to the development.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>The European eel stock has declined significantly since the 1980s, and the Eel Recovery Plan of the European Commission requires Member States to develop river basin Eel Management Plans (EMPs) that will achieve an escapement of silver eels that equals or exceeds 40% of the escapement biomass that would be produced in the absence of human activities. However, because silver eel esca- pement is not quantified within the UK, a modelling approach is required to estimate potential and actual escapement, and to assess the likely effects of management measures. We focus on two approaches developed in the UK, the Reference Condition Model (RCM) and the Scenario-based Model for Eel Populations (SMEP), and illustrate how such approaches can be used in EMPs using selected data from the River Severn. The RCM results indicate that the yellow eel population in the River Severn basin may be just 30–40% of the potential density indicated by reference conditions derived from a selection of rivers between the late 1970s and the early 1980s. The challenges of applying a model designed to be as realistic of eel production as possible, and the limited data on natural eel habitat and eel production in the Severn, preclude a SMEP analysis similar to that of the RCM, but simulations based on a simplified basin description and eel survey data from the early 1980s illustrate the potential of this model to assess compliance and test management scenarios. Keywords:</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Zitek, A.</author><author>Schmutz, S.</author><author>Jungwirth, M.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Assessing the efficiency of connectivity measures with regard to the EU-Water Framework Directive in a Danube-tributary system</title><secondary-title>Hydrobiologia</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Hydrobiologia</full-title></periodical><pages>139-161</pages><volume>609</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>Assessment</keyword><keyword>Connectivity</keyword><keyword>Danube catchment</keyword><keyword>Ecological status</keyword><keyword>Fish migration</keyword><keyword>Rehabilitation</keyword><keyword>River</keyword><keyword>Water Framework Directive</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2008</year></dates><isbn>0018-8158</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1007/s10750-008-9394-0</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Assessing_the_Efficiency_of_Connectivity_Measures_.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>The effect of restoring connectivity for fish by the construction of 11 fish ladders in the Pielach and Melk rivers, both tributaries to the Danube in Austria, was monitored using electric fishing and fish traps between 1999 and 2004. In order to assess the efficiency of connectivity rehabilitation measures pre- and post-project data combining electric fishing and trap catch data were analyzed by means of three fish-based assessment methods: a MUlti-Level concept for a Fish-based, river-type-specific Assessment of ecological integrity (MULFA), the Fish Index Austria (FIA) and the European Fish Index (EFI). The effect of adding qualitative trap catch data to electric fishing data on metrics and indices was also tested and the magnitude of the effect was related to the distance of the sites from the river mouth. The results clearly demonstrated the significant contribution of connectivity rehabilitation measures to the ecological integrity of rivers like the River Pielach where morphological conditions are good, whereas remaining channelization still limits the success of connectivity measures in the River Melk. Trap catch data were found to represent an essential source of additional information to assess the efficiency of connectivity measures shortly after their implementation. The negative correlations of the magnitude of the effect of different indices and metrics with the distance of assessment sites from river mouths obviously underline the importance of the river Danube as a source for the re-colonization process. While the indices tested were found to have limited ability to reflect short-term response of fish assemblages to continuum rehabilitation, guild metrics were able to detect improvements of the ecological status shortly after the implementation of connectivity measures. Six metrics showed significant differences between pre and post-project data reflecting the expected increase of the ecological integrity: (1) Fish Region Index (FRI; FIA, MULFA), (2) number of subdominant species and (3) number of flow-guilds (FIA), (4) number of type specific species (MULFA), (5) number of benthic species and (6) number of potamodromous species (EFI); the FRI differences were only significant when trap catch data were added. The EFI indicated a decline of ecological integrity through increases in the density of omnivorous species and the relative number of tolerant species as well as a decrease in the relative number of intolerant species. Significantly decreasing responses with the distance from the river mouth were documented by the EFI and MULFA-index, the FRI (FIA, MULFA), total biomass and for the number of type specific species (MULFA).</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kroes, Daniel E.</author><author>Brinson, Mark M.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Occurrence of riverine wetlands on floodplains along a climatic gradient</title><secondary-title>Wetlands</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Wetlands</full-title></periodical><pages>167-177</pages><volume>24</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>Anguilla anguilla - Reclaimed marsh - Habitat - Sp</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2004</year></dates><isbn>0277-5212</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1672/0277-5212(2004)024</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Laffaille, 2004 - electrofishing eels in France.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>The relation between the occurrence of riverine wetlands in floodplains along a humid to semi- arid climatic continuum was studied in two regions. The first included 36 mid-reach streams from Colorado to Iowa, USA, a region with a broad range of PET ratios (potential evapotranspiration/precipitation) from 0.70 to 1.75. The second region included 16 headwater streams in eastern North Carolina with PET ratios ranging from 0.67 to 0.83. Wetland boundaries were identified in the field along transects perpendicular to the floodplain. The width of jurisdictional wetlands was compared with flood-prone width (FPW) and ex- pressed as a percent. An increase in PET ratio corresponded to an exponential decrease in the percentage of the FPW that is wetland. Soil texture, duration of overbank flow, and stream order did not correlate with percentage of FPW that was wetland. Streams with a PET ratio greater than 0.98 did not have wetlands associated with them. Greater channel cross-sectional areas correlated positively with greater wetland widths in both study regions. Overbank flow did not appear to contribute to wetland prevalence. Supplemental ground-water sources, however, as indicated by greater base flows, could not be ruled out as sources con- tributing to wetland occurrence. Key</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Water Framework Directive – United Kingdom Advisory Group (WFD-UKTAG)</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>UKTAG River Assessment Method River continuity - Barrier to fish migration method (Scotland)</title></titles><periodical/><pages>1-5</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2015</year></dates><isbn>9781906934606</isbn><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Barrier to fish migration (Scotland) Method Statement.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Sheer, M. B.</author><author>Steel, E. A.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Lost Watersheds: Barriers, Aquatic Habitat Connectivity, and Salmon Persistence in the Willamette and Lower Columbia River Basins</title><secondary-title>Transactions of the American Fisheries Society</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Transactions of the American Fisheries Society</full-title></periodical><pages>1654-1669</pages><volume>135</volume><issue>6</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2006</year></dates><isbn>0002-8487</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1577/T05-221.1</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Sheer &amp; Steel, 2006.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1577/T05-221.1</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>—Large portions of watersheds and streams are lost to anadromous fishes because of anthropogenic barriers to migration. The loss of these streams and rivers has shifted the distribution of accessible habitat, often reducing the diversity of accessible habitat and the quantity of high-quality habitat. We combined existing inventories of barriers to adult fish passage in the Willamette and Lower Columbia River basins and identified 1,491 anthropogenic barriers to fish passage blocking 14,931 km of streams. We quantified and compared the stream quality, land cover, and physical characteristics of lost versus currently accessible habitat by watershed, assessed the effect of barriers on the variability of accessible habitats, and investigated potential impacts of habitat reduction on endangered or threatened salmonid populations. The majority of the study watersheds have lost more than 40% of total fish stream habitat. Overall, 40% of the streams with spawning gradients suitable for steelhead (anadromous rainbow trout Oncorhynchus mykiss), 60% of streams with riparian habitat in good condition, and 30% of streams draining watersheds with all coniferous land cover are no longer accessible to anadromous fish. Across watersheds, hydrologic and topographic watershed characteristics were correlated with barrier location, barrier density, and the impacts of barriers on habitat. Population-based abundance scores for spring Chinook salmon O. tshawytscha were strongly correlated with the magnitude of habitat lost and the number of lowland fish passage barriers. The characteristics of barrier and habitat distribution presented in this paper indicate that barrier removal projects and mitigation for instream barriers should consider both the magnitude and quality of the lost habitat.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Latham, J</author><author>Gillespie, J</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Applying connectivity mapping to spatial planning in Wales</title></titles><periodical/><keywords><keyword>biodiversity</keyword><keyword>ecological connectivity</keyword><keyword>green</keyword><keyword>habitat networks</keyword><keyword>infrastructure</keyword><keyword>spatial planning</keyword><keyword>wales</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2006</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Latham, Gillespie - 2006 - Applying connectivity mapping to spatial planning in Wales.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Redding, Martin</author><author>Manager, Assistant Engineering</author><author>Officer, Environmental</author><author>Fourth, Witham</author><author>Internal, District</author><author>Board, Drainage</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>The Fens Integrated Biodiversity Delivery Area ‘</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><dates><year>2010</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://thefensibda-flier-2 (1).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Hazel, Ballachuan</author><author>Wildlife, Wood</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Nature in brief</title></titles><periodical/><pages>2013</pages><issue>February</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2013</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Scottish Wildlife Trust National Ecological Network brief.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Cui, Baoshan</author><author>Zhang, Zhiming</author><author>Lei, Xiaoxia</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Implementation of Diversified Ecological Networks to Strengthen Wetland Conservation</title><secondary-title>Clean - Soil, Air, Water</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Clean - Soil, Air, Water</full-title></periodical><pages>1015-1026</pages><volume>40</volume><issue>10</issue><keywords><keyword>Ecosystem connectivity</keyword><keyword>Ecosystem conservation</keyword><keyword>Multiple scales</keyword><keyword>Wetland network</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2012</year></dates><isbn>1863-0650</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/clen.201200026</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Cui et al. 2012.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>the notion that the conservation of wetlands in the world is too limited has gained a universal consensus because of the conflicts between their great value and drastic decline in their quantity and quality. To mitigate these conflicts, ecological networks have integrated the hydrologic and biological connectivity of ecosystems. The basic elements of ecological networks, patches, and corridors have been extracted to reflect the attributes of the hydrologic and biological connectivity of ecosystems. This paper reviews recent application of network approaches to ecological conservation, focusing on their application in wetland ecosystems, and proposing a new perspective for wetland conservation. This review is limited to four aspects: first, the linkages between wetlands and ecological networks are determined by reviewing the development both of the them; second, the two types of connectivity and their application that can be obtained from graphs or networks models are discussed; third, common netwrok analysis approaches, which can provide a theoretical basis to explore the optimal relationship between network structure and function, are summarized, finally, this paper presents the configuration and convergence characteristics of different types of wetland networks at multiple spatial scales. At the conclusion, suggestions for further work are presented.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Trust, The Wildlife</author><author>Merseyside, North</author><author>Environment, Lancashire</author><author>Network, Record</author><author>Local, Lancashire</author><author>Partnership, Nature</author><author>England, Natural</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Lancashire Ecological Network Approach and Analysis ( Version Ia )</title></titles><periodical/><issue>Version I</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2013</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Lancashire Ecological Network Approach and Analysis Document v1.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Branco, Paulo</author><author>Amaral, Susana D.</author><author>Ferreira, Maria T.</author><author>Santos, José M.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Do small barriers affect the movement of freshwater fish by increasing residency?</title><secondary-title>Science of The Total Environment</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Science of The Total Environment</full-title></periodical><pages>486-494</pages><volume>581-582</volume><keywords/><dates><year>2017</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/J.SCITOTENV.2016.12.156</electronic-resource-num><urls><web-urls><url>https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S0048969716328455#f0015</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>River fragmentation due to artificial barriers directly impacts fish communities by limiting migratory movements. This work aims to understand how small barriers affect the movements of a potamodromous cyprinid species – the Iberian barbel (Luciobarbus bocagei (Steindachner, 1864)) – in a 5.6km upstream segment of a stream impacted only by the presence of physical barriers. Fish were marked with Visible Implant Elastomer tags (VIE), and barriers were seasonally characterized. A total of 683 fish were tagged, with 104 recaptures, during five sampling seasons (spring 2012 – early summer 2013). Eleven of the recaptured fish moved past a barrier, without any preference in terms of direction of movement. There were no differences in length, either between migrants and residents, or between upstream and downstream migrants. The results show that although barbel are able to negotiate small barriers, part of the population did not move between fragmented reaches – an indication that under such conditions, fish species populations may adjust their life-history strategy to augment residency as it was hypothesized from the results.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>ESRI</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Spatial Analyst Tutorial</title><secondary-title>Esri</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Esri</full-title></periodical><pages>1-60</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2010</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>http://dx.doi.org/10.1641/0006-3568(2004)054[1092:GGAPRF]2.0.CO;2</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://spatial-analyst-tutorial.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>This tutorial introduce us to the Spacial Analyst Tool. It gives hands on training with different tools. The data for this tutorial are stored at C/temp/VirtualCAmpus/SpatialAnalyst</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><titles><title>Working with Elevation Data to Produce High-Quality Results GIS workflows developed in response to Hurricane Sandy data</title></titles><periodical/><issue>May</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2017</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://NPS_NCBN_Working_with_Elevation_Data_to_Produce_High_Quality_Results_May2017Update_2240160.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Baxter, R.</author><author>Hastings, N.</author><author>Law, a.</author><author>Glass, E. J..</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>[ No Title ]</title><secondary-title>Animal Genetics</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Animal Genetics</full-title></periodical><pages>561-563</pages><volume>39</volume><issue>5</issue><keywords><keyword>1999</keyword><keyword>also</keyword><keyword>antigen</keyword><keyword>bola</keyword><keyword>bola-drb3</keyword><keyword>bovine</keyword><keyword>called the bovine leucocyte</keyword><keyword>complex</keyword><keyword>genotyping</keyword><keyword>includes many immune-related genes</keyword><keyword>lewin et al</keyword><keyword>mhc</keyword><keyword>of cattle</keyword><keyword>the major histocompatibility complex</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2008</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Suffold Wildlife Trust Ecological Networks Methodology.PDF</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Radinger, Johannes</author><author>Hölker, Franz</author><author>Horký, Pavel</author><author>Slavík, Ondřej</author><author>Wolter, Christian</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Improved river continuity facilitates fishes' abilities to track future environmental changes</title><secondary-title>Journal of Environmental Management</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Environmental Management</full-title></periodical><pages>169-179</pages><volume>208</volume><issue>January</issue><keywords><keyword>Barrier prioritization</keyword><keyword>Climate change</keyword><keyword>Habitat shift</keyword><keyword>Longitudinal connectivity</keyword><keyword>River Elbe</keyword><keyword>River basin management</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2018</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.jenvman.2017.12.011</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Radinger et al., 2018.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Barriers represent one of the largest anthropogenic impacts on the ecological status of rivers, and they also potentially restrict fishes' ability to respond to future environmental changes. Thus, river management aims to restore the longitudinal connectivity of rivers to allow continuous migration and movement of water, sediments and biota. However, it is often unclear whether the targeted barriers are also those most relevant for fish species, particularly to track future habitat shifts caused by environmental change. In this study, we applied species distribution models and the GIS-based fish dispersal model FIDIMO to evaluate the impacts of barriers (e.g. weirs and dams) on the dispersal of 17 native fish species in the European River Elbe with a particular focus on climate- and land use-induced habitat shifts. Specifically, we compared three scenarios of longitudinal connectivity: (i) current longitudinal connectivity, (ii) connectivity improvements as planned by river managers for 2021 and (iii) a reference with full longitudinal connectivity. The models indicated that barriers restricted the movement of two modeled fish species on average, thus impeding fishes' abilities to track future habitat shifts. Moreover, the number of species affected by barriers increased downstream. For the River Elbe, our results suggest that river management has most likely identified the most relevant barriers in respect to the modeled species and future environmental change. We emphasize that river management and barrier prioritization must thoroughly consider species-specific movement and dispersal abilities, as well as the specific spatial arrangement of barriers in the river system in relation to the spatial distribution of species' populations and suitable habitats.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Davis, Chanté D.</author><author>Epps, Clinton W.</author><author>Flitcroft, Rebecca L.</author><author>Banks, Michael A.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Refining and defining riverscape genetics: How rivers influence population genetic structure</title><secondary-title>Wiley Interdisciplinary Reviews: Water</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Wiley Interdisciplinary Reviews: Water</full-title></periodical><pages>e1269</pages><issue>November 2017</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2018</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/wat2.1269</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Davis et al. 2017.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://doi.wiley.com/10.1002/wat2.1269</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>On July 9, 2012, President Obama signed into law the Food and Drug Administration Safety and Innovation Act (FDASIA), Pub. L. No. 112-114, which will provide more than $6 billion in industry user fees to FDA over the next five years to help fund the Agency’s review process for drugs and medical devices. FDASIA also creates new user fees for generic drugs and biosimilars and includes a number of provisions that improve the regulatory process. FDASIA contains several ofMedIC’s priorities, including: ? Creation of a risk-benefit framework for the drug approval process that will provide a consistent and balanced approach to FDA’s decision making; ? Expansion of the accelerated approval process to new medical treatments; ? Provision of a new pathway for breakthrough therapies; ? Provision of incentives for antibiotic development; ? Improvement of the FDA’s advisory committee conflict of interest rules; ? Clarification of the least burdensome standards for medical devices; ? Modification of the de novo application process; and ? Acceleration of the appeals process for medical devices.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Programme, Improvement</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Hydrological functioning theme plan</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><dates><year>2000</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Programme - 2000 - Hydrological functioning theme plan.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://publications.naturalengland.org.uk/publication/6400975361277952?category=35016</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Fullerton, A. H.</author><author>Burnett, K. M.</author><author>Steel, E. A.</author><author>Flitcroft, R. L.</author><author>Pess, G. R.</author><author>Feist, B. E.</author><author>Torgersen, C. E.</author><author>Miller, D. J.</author><author>Sanderson, B. L.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Hydrological connectivity for riverine fish: Measurement challenges and research opportunities</title><secondary-title>Freshwater Biology</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Freshwater Biology</full-title></periodical><pages>2215-2237</pages><volume>55</volume><issue>11</issue><keywords><keyword>Migratory fish</keyword><keyword>Movement barriers</keyword><keyword>River network</keyword><keyword>Spatial structure</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2010</year></dates><isbn>00465070</isbn><accession-num>18845952</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1365-2427.2010.02448.x</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Fullerton et al., 2010.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>1. In this review,wefirst summarizehowhydrologic connectivity has been studied for riverine fish capable ofmoving long distances, and then identify research opportunities that have clear conservation significance. Migratory species, such as anadromous salmonids, are goodmodel organisms for understanding ecological connectivity in rivers because the spatial scale over whichmovements occuramong freshwater habitats is large enough to be easily observed with available techniques; they are often economically or culturally valuable with habitats that can be easily fragmented by human activities; and they integrate landscape conditions from multiple surrounding catchment(s) with in-river conditions. Studies have focussed on three themes: (i) relatively stable connections (connections controlled by processes that act over broad spatio-temporal scales &gt;1000 km2 and &gt;100 years); (ii) dynamic connections (connections controlled by processes acting overfine tomoderate spatio-temporal scales_1–1000 km2 and &lt;1–100 years); and (iii) anthropogenic influences on hydrologic connectivity, including actions that disrupt or enhance natural connections experienced by fish. 2. We outline eight challenges to understanding the role of connectivity in riverine fish ecology, organized under three foci: (i) addressing the constraints of river structure; (ii) embracing temporal complexity in hydrologic connectivity; and (iii) managing connectivity for riverine fishes. Challenges include the spatial structure of stream networks, the force and direction of flow, scale-dependence of connectivity, shifting boundaries, complexity of behaviour and life histories and quantifying anthropogenic influence on connectivity and aligning management goals. As we discuss each challenge, we summarize relevant approaches in the literature and provide additional suggestions for improving research and management of connectivity for riverine fishes. 3. Specifically, we suggest that rapid advances are possible in the following arenas: (i) incorporating network structure and river discharge into analyses; (ii) increasing explicit consideration of temporal complexity and fish behaviour in the scope of analyses; and (iii) parsing degrees of human and natural influences on connectivity and defining acceptable alterations. Multiscale analyses are most likely to identify dominant patterns of connections and disconnections, and the appropriate scale at which to focus conservation activities.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Land, R</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Broadland District Ecological Network Mapping Compiled by</title></titles><periodical/><issue>January</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2007</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Broadland ecological network report 2007.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><titles><title>With Thanks : About this Report</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Unknown - Unknown - With Thanks About this Report.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Tarboton, David G.</author><author>Bras, Rafael L.</author><author>Rodriguez‐Iturbe, Ignacio</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>On the extraction of channel networks from digital elevation data</title><secondary-title>Hydrological Processes</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Hydrological Processes</full-title></periodical><pages>81-100</pages><volume>5</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>Cartography</keyword><keyword>Digital Elevation Models</keyword><keyword>Drainage density</keyword><keyword>Fluvial geomorphology</keyword><keyword>Mapping</keyword><keyword>River basins</keyword></keywords><dates><year>1991</year></dates><isbn>1099-1085</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1002/hyp.3360050107</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Tarboton, Bras, Rodriguez‐Iturbe - 1991 - On the extraction of channel networks from digital elevation data.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Channel networks with artibtrary drainage density or resolution can be extracted from digital elevation data. However, for digital elevation data derived networks to be useful they have to be extracted at the correct length scale or drainage density. Here we suggest a criterion for determining the appropriate drainage density at which to extract networks from digital elevation data. The criterion is basically to extract the highest resolution (highest drainage density) network that satisfies scaling laws that have traditionally been found to hold for channel networks. Procedures that use this criterion are presented and tested on 21 digital elevation data sets well distributed throughout the U.S.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Edeline, Eric</author><author>Dufour, Sylvie</author><author>Elie, Pierre</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Role of glass eel salinity preference in the control of habitat selection and growth plasticity in Anguilla anguilla</title><secondary-title>Marine Ecology Progress Series</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Marine Ecology Progress Series</full-title></periodical><pages>191-199</pages><volume>304</volume><keywords><keyword>Anguilla anguilla</keyword><keyword>Divergent migratory tactics</keyword><keyword>Glass eel</keyword><keyword>Growth</keyword><keyword>Habitat selection</keyword><keyword>Life history plasticity</keyword><keyword>Locomotor activity</keyword><keyword>Salinity preference</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2005</year></dates><isbn>0171-8630</isbn><accession-num>10943652</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.3354/meps304191</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Edeline et al., 2005.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Eels colonize either marine, estuarine or freshwater habitats, with marine and estuarine eels tending to grow faster than freshwater eels. The reasons for these divergent migratory tactics and growth trajectories remain poorly understood. In order to investigate the role of salinity preferences of glass eels in the control of habitat selection and growth plasticity, we sorted different contingents of glass eels Anguilla anguilla through 2 consecutive salinity preference tests. This allowed us to study the link between salinity preference and locomotor activity (i.e. positive rheotaxis), and to distinguish contingents of glass eels that were either plastic or fixed in their preference for freshwater (FW) or saltwater (SW). Subsequently, we monitored somatic growth of the different contingents in controlled SW and FW rearing conditions. Preference for FW was linked to high locomotor activity, a behavioral pattern likely to promote colonization of FW habitats in the wild. Accordingly, FWC (FW contingent, i.e. glass eels that preferred FW twice) exhibited poor growth, similar to those observed in wild FW eel populations. In contrast, preference for SW was linked to low locomotor activity, and the SWC (SW contingent, i.e. glass eels that preferred SW twice) had high growth rates in SW, as observed in wild marine and estuarine populations. The PCC (plastic contingent, i.e. glass eels that swappped their salinity preference) had an intermediary growth status that could be related to the 'nomad' life style of eels migrating between different habitat types during their life. Growth was significantly higher in SW compared to FW in all contingents, indicating that habitat salinity may directly affect growth, irrespective of food availability. Our results demonstrated that glass eel salinity preference was linked to their locomotor activity and growth performance, and provided a comprehensive ecological mechanism for the control of habitat distribution and growth patterns observed in wild eel populations.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Somerset, Wild</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Wild Somerset</title></titles><periodical/><issue>May</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2008</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://'Wild Somerset' a Biodiversity Strategy (1).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Book">1</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Report, Technical</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Fish Pass Design for Eel and Elver (Anguilla anguilla)</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><isbn>184432267X</isbn><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Report - Unknown - Fish Pass Design for Eel and Elver (Anguilla anguilla).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Applications, Source Ecological</author><author>Oct, No</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>The Impact of Low-Head Dams on Fish Species Richness in Wisconsin , USA Author ( s ): Graeme S . Cumming THE IMPACT OF LOW-HEAD DAMS ON FISH SPECIES RICHNESS IN WISCONSIN , USA</title></titles><periodical/><pages>1495-1506</pages><volume>14</volume><issue>5</issue><keywords><keyword>affect upstream nutrient cy-</keyword><keyword>biodiversity</keyword><keyword>connectivity</keyword><keyword>conservation</keyword><keyword>corridor</keyword><keyword>dams can in theory</keyword><keyword>dams on upstream commu-</keyword><keyword>fishes</keyword><keyword>gradient</keyword><keyword>impoundment</keyword><keyword>many species depends nities</keyword><keyword>the impacts of low-head</keyword><keyword>the long-term persistence of</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2012</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Cumming, 2004.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><titles><title>Climate Change Adaptation Manual Climate Change Adaptation Manual Natural England and the RSPB</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://NE546 Climate Change Adaptation Manual - Evidence to support nature conservation in a changing climate NE546 19 Feb 2015.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Environment Agency</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Stocking European Eels (Anguilla anguilla) - the eel manual</title><secondary-title>The Eel Manual</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>The Eel Manual</full-title></periodical><pages>2-31</pages><volume>1</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2010</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Stocking European Eels (Anguilla anguilla) - The eel manual geho0411btqe-e-e.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><titles><title>A Proposal for an Enhanced Ecological Network for Fenland</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://3fensproposedenhancedecologicalnetwork2012.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Lima, Marcelo</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Connectivity conservation scenarios for Cambridgeshire Fens and associated habitats</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://07MarceloLima.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><titles><title>A Field Guide for Assessing the Passability of Man-Made River Structures by European Eels</title></titles><periodical/><issue>October</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2018</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://ZSL_EelBarrierAssessmentTool_Final_0.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Web Page">16</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>ESRI</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>How Stream Orders Work</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><dates><year>2018</year></dates><urls><web-urls><url>http://pro.arcgis.com/en/pro-app/tool-reference/spatial-analyst/how-stream-order-works.htm</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Davidson, Nick</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>W ( h ) ither wetlands ? 1971 : The Ramsar Convention ’ s text</title></titles><periodical/><issue>December</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2015</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://11._Nick_Davidson.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Book">1</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Morris, K</author><author>Ferwerda, F</author><author>Papas, P</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Wetland connectivity models (Technical Report Series No. 241)</title></titles><periodical/><volume>2012</volume><issue>241</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2012</year></dates><isbn>9781742877181</isbn><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://ARI-Technical-Report-241-Wetland-connectivity-models.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Crick, Humphrey</author><author>Taylor, Sarah</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Trialling a national approach using Condatis , and the tool ’ s place in our Ecological Networks Handbook</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://04HumphreyCrickSarahTaylor.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Hodgson, Jenny A.</author><author>Thomas, Chris D.</author><author>Cinderby, Steve</author><author>Cambridge, Howard</author><author>Evans, Paul</author><author>Hill, Jane K.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Habitat re-creation strategies for promoting adaptation of species to climate change</title><secondary-title>Conservation Letters</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Conservation Letters</full-title></periodical><pages>289-297</pages><volume>4</volume><issue>4</issue><keywords><keyword>Colonization</keyword><keyword>Connectivity</keyword><keyword>Corridor</keyword><keyword>Habitat network</keyword><keyword>Habitat restoration</keyword><keyword>Incidence function model</keyword><keyword>Metapopulation</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2011</year></dates><isbn>1755-263X</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/j.1755-263X.2011.00177.x</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Hodgson_et_al-2011-Conservation_Letters.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Creation of new habitat could help species respond to climate change by\nfacilitating range expansion in fragmented landscapes. However, there\nare currently no guidelines for deciding where new habitat should be\nplaced to promote range changes. We developed a model to simulate the\nexpansion of populations across a heavily fragmented landscape in the\nUnited Kingdom, and investigated the effectiveness of six habitat\ncreation strategies for woodland, grassland, heathland, and wetland\nhabitats. A strategy aimed at linking clusters of habitat patches was\nmost effective for three of the four habitat types. Adding habitat\nevenly or randomly across the landscape, or according to stakeholder\nsuggestions, were consistently better strategies than increasing\naggregation of habitat. The results highlight that the best spatial\npattern to facilitate range expansion is different from the best pattern\nto prevent extinction.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>England, Natural</author><author>Team, Project</author><author>Edwards, Jeff</author><author>Knight, Michael</author><author>Taylor, Sarah</author><author>Crosher, Ian</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>National Habitat Network Mapping Project</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://18th July Presentation to Landscape Partnership.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Page, Ecological Networks</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Hertf ordshire ’ s Ecological Networks A report on the current situation and priorities for restoration</title></titles><periodical/><pages>1-49</pages><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Hertfordshire Wildlife Mapping project report - Final.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>De Meyer, J.</author><author>Christiaens, J.</author><author>Adriaens, D.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Diet-induced phenotypic plasticity in European eel (Anguilla anguilla)</title><secondary-title>Journal of Experimental Biology</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Experimental Biology</full-title></periodical><pages>354-363</pages><volume>219</volume><issue>3</issue><keywords><keyword>dimorphism</keyword><keyword>elver eel stage</keyword><keyword>trophic plasticity</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><isbn>1477-91450022-0949</isbn><accession-num>26847560</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1242/jeb.131714</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://De Meyer, Christiaens, Adriaens - 2016 - Diet-induced phenotypic plasticity in European eel (Anguilla anguilla)(2).pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://jeb.biologists.org/cgi/doi/10.1242/jeb.131714</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Two phenotypes are present within the European eel population: broad-heads and narrow-heads. The expression of these phenotypes has been linked to several factors, such as diet and differential growth. The exact factors causing this dimorphism, however, are still unknown. In this study, we performed a feeding experiment on glass eels from the moment they start to feed. Eels were either fed a hard diet, which required biting and spinning behavior, or a soft diet, which required suction feeding. We found that the hard feeders develop a broader head and a larger adductor mandibulae region than eels that were fed a soft diet, implying that the hard feeders are capable of larger bite forces. Next to this, soft feeders develop a sharper and narrower head, which could reduce hydrodynamic drag, allowing more rapid strikes towards their prey. Both phenotypes were found in a control group, which were given a combination of both diets. These phenotypes were, however, not as extreme as the hard or the soft feeding group, indicating that some specimens are more likely to consume hard prey and others soft prey, but that they do not selectively eat one of both diets. In conclusion, we found that diet is a major factor influencing head shape in European eel and this ability to specialize in feeding on hard or soft prey could decrease intra-specific competition in European eel populations.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><titles><title>Climate Change Adaptation Manual Climate Change Adaptation Manual Natural England and the RSPB</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://NE546 Climate Change Adaptation Manual - Evidence to support nature conservation in a changing climate NE546 19 Feb 2015.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Burgess, Peter</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Thinking Starting</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://7._Peter_Burgess_CIEEM_2015_11.12.15.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Bull, Colin</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Riverine obstacles to fish movement : a rapid assessment tool The issue : What is a obstacle to fish migration ?</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Fish_pass_assessment_tool_Colin_Bull.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Generic">31</ref-type><titles><title>all-South-Drain-WLMP-maps-Aug10.pdf</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Unknown - Unknown - all-South-Drain-WLMP-maps-Aug10.pdf.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>England, Natural</author><author>Chapter, See</author><author>Chapter, See</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Identifying spatial priorities for Ecological Networks Chapter 4 A guide to map-based models and tools for planning ecological networks</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://England, Chapter, Chapter - Unknown - Identifying spatial priorities for Ecological Networks Chapter 4 A guide to map-based models an(2).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Edwards, Jeff</author><author>Knight, Michael</author><author>Taylor, Sarah</author><author>Crosher, Ian</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Creating a national habitat network map</title></titles><periodical/><pages>2</pages><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://HabNet Poster 16May2018 FINAL.PDF</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Rennie, P</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A strategic plan for research</title></titles><periodical/><issue>June</issue><keywords/><dates><year>1994</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://1fensplanfinalreport2012.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Brue, Upper</author><author>Boards, Drainage</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>South Drain Water Level Management Plan Lower Brue Drainage Board and Upper Brue Drainage Board Approved April 2010 Contents</title></titles><periodical/><pages>1-53</pages><issue>April</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2010</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Brue, Boards - 2010 - South Drain Water Level Management Plan Lower Brue Drainage Board and Upper Brue Drainage Board Approved April 201.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Landscapes, Living</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Living landscapes</title></titles><periodical/><pages>2012-2015</pages><issue>208123</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2013</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Surry WT living_living_landscape_strategy_2014_digital.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Mcinnes, Robert</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Promoting a landscape-scale approach to wetlands : the filth and the fury</title></titles><periodical/><issue>December</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2015</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://10._McINNES_CIEEM_151215.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><titles><title>This Presentation is attributable to Willem Ferwerda and may not be reproduced or copied</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://002_293__ecologicalnetworksconnectivityandconservationbacktobasics_drrogercatchpole_1361292115.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Jongman, Robert H G</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Ecological Networks are an issue for all of us.</title><secondary-title>Journal of Landscape Ecology</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Landscape Ecology</full-title></periodical><pages>7-13</pages><volume>1</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2008</year></dates><isbn>1028501200018</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.2478/v10285-012-0001-8</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Jongman et al., 2004.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>The concept of ecological networks is not new. Ecological networks have been developed in several European countries, including in Estonia during the 1970s and 1980s and in former Czechoslovakia during the 1980s. In these countries, a strong tradition in land-use planning had created the institutional environment for allocating functions at the landscape scale and habitats were becoming increasingly fragmented due to economic development. We now recognise this as the translation of landscape ecological knowledge in homogenisation and fragmentation processes in the landscapes of Europe that diminished ecosystem functions and natural populations. Fragmentation explains much of the decline in natural species, and we now realize that, for many natural species, existing nature reserves and national parks are too small (Somma, 2006). The concept of ecological connectivity is implicit in several international conventions (e.g. Ramsar convention, Bern Convention), European agreements (Habitats and Species directives), and related EU policy implementation (Natura 2000). It has also become operational in national and European strategies (National Ecological Networks, the Pan-European Ecological Network and Pan European Biological and Landscape Diversity Strategy (PEBLDS). The meaning and the application of the ecological network concept has changed over the past decade, with emphasis shifting from nature protection towards sustainable development for a region as a whole that integrates biodiversity issues. The observed change in thinking originates from the discourse in the international policy arena of the Convention on Biodiversity, the World Summit on Sustainable Development, and the Millennium Development Goals, which perceived the environment as making a contribution to sustainable development, rather than as something with intrinsic value to be protected from use. Implementation of these international agendas is increasingly guided by the ecosystem approach. This approach can be regarded as a strategy for the management of land, water and living resources that promotes conservation and sustainable use in an equitable way. One consequence of perceiving an ecological network as a means towards sustainable development is the increasing number and diversity of stakeholders and land-use interests that need to be incorporated into the design and that should be part of the management process. In addition, it is evident that the institutionalisation of such a landscape change will greatly benefit from the overall support of the stakeholders, or as Bennett (2004) puts it: &quot;No programme of the breadth and ambition of an ecological network can achieve results without the active support of local communities and key stakeholders.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Generic">31</ref-type><titles><title>all-North-Drain-WLMP-maps-Aug10.pdf</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Unknown - Unknown - all-North-Drain-WLMP-maps-Aug10.pdf.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Janssen, R.</author><author>Goosen, H.</author><author>Verhoeven, M. L.</author><author>Verhoeven, J. T.A.</author><author>Omtzigt, A. Q.A.</author><author>Maltby, E.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Decision support for integrated wetland management</title><secondary-title>Environmental Modelling and Software</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Environmental Modelling and Software</full-title></periodical><pages>215-229</pages><volume>20</volume><issue>2</issue><keywords><keyword>GIS</keyword><keyword>Impact assessment</keyword><keyword>Multicriteria analysis</keyword><keyword>Wetland management</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2005</year></dates><isbn>1364-8152</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.envsoft.2003.12.020</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Janssen et al. 2005.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Wetlands perform functions that support the generation of ecologically, socially and economically important values. European legislation has increasingly recognised the importance of preserving wetland ecosystems. The Water Framework Directive (WFD) embodies many of the existing directives that have implications for wetlands. The EU funded EVALUWET project (European valuation and assessment tool supporting wetland ecosystem legislation) aims to develop and implement an operational wetland evaluation decision support system to support European policy objectives. A multidisciplinary approach is adopted combining expertise from natural and social scientists. The region of Noord-Hollands Midden is selected as the Dutch case study within EVALUWET. This region north of Amsterdam is a typical Dutch landscape with drained peat meadows in polders below sea level. Important stakeholders are: agricultural organisations, recreation, nature conservation organisations, and provincial/regional authorities. Water levels are controlled in the area. Changes in water regimes are proposed (National Policies, WFD) which will have an impact on the performance of functions such as agriculture, nature and residential and recreation opportunities. In this case study, three alternatives will be compared: (1) modern peat pasture (current), (2) historical peat pasture and (3) dynamic mire. Impacts of these alternatives on a number of criteria relevant to EU policy are assessed. Spatial evaluation techniques in combination with multicriteria methods are used to support evaluation. This provides a better insight into the consequences of alternative water regimes on the performance of the wetland functions and is used to support stakeholders participating in the decision process. The system is based on the following software components: impact assessment is performed by a rule-based knowledge base implemented in NetWeaver. Spatial evaluation and map presentation are handled in ArcView and ArcMap. Multicriteria analysis is performed using the software package DEFINITE. © 2004 Elsevier Ltd. All rights reserved.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Piper, Adam T.</author><author>Manes, Costantino</author><author>Siniscalchi, Fabio</author><author>Marion, Andrea</author><author>Wright, Rosalind M.</author><author>Kemp, Paul S.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Response of seaward-migrating european eel (Anguilla anguilla) to manipulated flow fields</title><secondary-title>Proceedings of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Proceedings of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences</full-title></periodical><pages>1-9</pages><volume>282</volume><issue>1811</issue><keywords><keyword>Acoustic telemetry</keyword><keyword>Behavioural fish guidance</keyword><keyword>Computational fluid dynamics</keyword><keyword>Ecohydraulics</keyword><keyword>Hydrodynamics</keyword><keyword>Hydropower</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2015</year></dates><isbn>0962-8452</isbn><accession-num>26136454</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1098/rspb.2015.1098</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Piper et al. - 2015 - Response of seaward-migrating european eel (Anguilla anguilla) to manipulated flow fields.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Anthropogenic structures (e.g. weirs and dams) fragment river networks and restrict the movement of migratory fish. Poor understanding of behavioural response to hydrodynamic cues at structures currently limits the development of effective barrier mitigation measures. This study aimed to assess the effect of flow constriction and associated flow patterns on eel behaviour during downstream migration. In a field experiment, we tracked the movements of 40 tagged adult European eels (Anguilla anguilla) through the forebay of a redundant hydropower intake under two manipulated hydrodynamic treatments. Interrogation of fish trajectories in relation to measured and modeled water velocities provided new insights into behaviour, fundamental for developing passage technologies for this endangered species. Eels rarely followed direct routes through the site. Initially, fish aligned with streamlines near the channel banks and approached the intake semi-passively. A switch to more energetically costly avoidance behaviours occurred on encountering constricted flow, prior to physical contact with structures. Under high water velocity gradients, fish then tended to escape rapidly back upstream, whereas exploratory 'search' behaviour was common when acceleration was low. This study highlights the importance of hydrodynamics in informing eel behaviour. This offers potential to develop behavioural guidance, improve fish passage solutions and enhance traditional physical screening.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Ray, Nicolas</author><author>Lehmann, Anthony</author><author>Ray, Nicolas</author><author>Lehmann, Anthony</author><author>Joly, Pierre</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Modelling spatial distribution of amphibian populations : a GIS approach based on matrix permeability . Biodivers Conserv matrix permeability</title></titles><periodical/><pages>2143-2165</pages><issue>April 2016</issue><keywords><keyword>abbreviations</keyword><keyword>amphibian</keyword><keyword>bufo bufo</keyword><keyword>dispersal model</keyword><keyword>ecologie et de biologie</keyword><keyword>gam</keyword><keyword>generalized additive model</keyword><keyword>generalized regression analysis and</keyword><keyword>geographic information system</keyword><keyword>geographical informa-</keyword><keyword>gis</keyword><keyword>grasp</keyword><keyword>laboratoire d</keyword><keyword>least-cost path</keyword><keyword>leba</keyword><keyword>migration modeling</keyword><keyword>permeability</keyword><keyword>spatial predictions</keyword><keyword>switzerland</keyword><keyword>tion system</keyword><keyword>triturus alpestris</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2002</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1023/A</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Ray et al. 2001.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Teresa Fenn</author><author>Salado, Rocio</author><author>Daly, Elizabeth</author><author>King, Andy</author><author>Jeffreys, Kate</author><author>Keyworth, Steve</author><author>Goupillon, Eleanor</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Environmental and socio-economic impacts of climate change on the Brue Valley</title><secondary-title>Final Report for Somerset Wildlife Trust and the Brue Valley Living Landscape Project</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Final Report for Somerset Wildlife Trust and the Brue Valley Living Landscape Project</full-title></periodical><pages>1-268</pages><issue>May</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2011</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Teresa Fenn et al. - 2011 - Environmental and socio-economic impacts of climate change on the Brue Valley.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.somersetwildlife.org/hres/fr 13 may.pdf</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><titles><title>End of project report and full technical specification</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Unknown - Unknown - End of project report and full technical specification.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Beatty, William S.</author><author>Kesler, Dylan C.</author><author>Webb, Elisabeth B.</author><author>Raedeke, Andrew H.</author><author>Naylor, Luke W.</author><author>Humburg, Dale D.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>The role of protected area wetlands in waterfowl habitat conservation: Implications for protected area network design</title><secondary-title>Biological Conservation</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Biological Conservation</full-title></periodical><pages>144-152</pages><volume>176</volume><keywords><keyword>Anas platyrhynchos</keyword><keyword>Conservation behavior</keyword><keyword>Dabbling duck</keyword><keyword>Mallard</keyword><keyword>Resource selection</keyword><keyword>Use-availability design</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year></dates><isbn>00063207</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.biocon.2014.05.018</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Beatty et al., 2014.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>The principal goal of protected area networks is biodiversity preservation, but efficacy of such networks is directly linked to animal movement within and outside area boundaries. We examined wetland selection patterns of mallards (Anas platyrhynchos) during non-breeding periods from 2010 to 2012 to evaluate the utility of protected areas to migratory waterfowl in North America. We tracked 33 adult females using global positioning system (GPS) satellite transmitters and implemented a use-availability resource selection design to examine mallard use of wetlands under varying degrees of protection. Specifically, we examined effects of proximities to National Wildlife Refuges, private land, state wildlife management areas, Wetland Reserve Program easements (WRP), and waterfowl sanctuaries on mallard wetland selection. In addition, we included landscape-level variables that measured areas of sanctuary and WRP within the surrounding landscape of each used and available wetland. We developed 8 wetland selection models according to season (autumn migration, winter, spring migration), hunting season (present, absent), and time period (diurnal, nocturnal). Model averaged parameter estimates indicated wetland selection patterns varied across seasons and time periods, but ducks consistently selected wetlands with greater areas of sanctuary and WRP in the surrounding landscape. Consequently, WRP has the potential to supplement protected area networks in the midcontinent region. Additionally, seasonal variation in wetland selection patterns indicated considering the effects of habitat management and anthropogenic disturbances on migratory waterfowl during the non-breeding period is essential in designing protected area networks. © 2014.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Brue, Upper</author><author>Boards, Drainage</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>North Drain Water Level Management Plan Lower Brue Drainage Board and Upper Brue Drainage Board Approved April 2010 Contents</title></titles><periodical/><pages>1-47</pages><issue>April</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2010</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Brue, Boards - 2010 - North Drain Water Level Management Plan Lower Brue Drainage Board and Upper Brue Drainage Board Approved April 201.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Saura, Santiago</author><author>Pascual-Hortal, Lucía</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A new habitat availability index to integrate connectivity in landscape conservation planning: Comparison with existing indices and application to a case study</title><secondary-title>Landscape and Urban Planning</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Landscape and Urban Planning</full-title></periodical><pages>91-103</pages><volume>83</volume><issue>2-3</issue><keywords><keyword>Connectivity metrics</keyword><keyword>Ecological networks</keyword><keyword>Graphs</keyword><keyword>Landscape connectivity</keyword><keyword>Patches prioritization</keyword><keyword>Reserve design</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2007</year></dates><isbn>0169-2046</isbn><accession-num>25623332</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.landurbplan.2007.03.005</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Saura_and_PascualHortal_2007.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Connectivity is a major concern for the maintenance of wildlife populations, ecological flows, and many other landscape functions. For these reasons many different connectivity indices have been used or proposed for landscape conservation planning; however, their properties and behaviour have not been sufficiently examined and may provide misleading or undesired results for these purposes. We here present a new index (probability of connectivity, PC) that is based on the habitat availability concept, dispersal probabilities between habitat patches and graph structures. We evaluate the performance of PC and compare it with other widespread indices through a set of 13 relevant properties that an index should ideally fulfil for adequately integrating connectivity in landscape planning applications. We found that PC is the only index that systematically accomplished all the requirements, overcoming some serious limitations of other available indices. We encourage the use of PC as a sound basis for planning decision-making. To demonstrate the use and potential of PC for practical landscape applications, we present an example of application to a case study for the goshawk (Accipiter gentilis) in Catalonia (NE Spain), where we identify those habitat areas that most contribute to overall landscape connectivity and evaluate the effectiveness and potential improvement of a protected areas network (Natura 2000) for conserving those critical habitat areas. © 2007 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wintle, Brendan A</author><author>Kujala, Heini</author><author>Whitehead, Amy</author><author>Cameron, Alison</author><author>Veloz, Sam</author><author>Kukkala, Aija</author><author>Moilanen, Atte</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Global synthesis of conservation studies reveals the importance of small habitat patches for biodiversity</title></titles><periodical/><pages>909-914</pages><volume>116</volume><issue>3</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2019</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1073/pnas.1813051115</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Wintle et al. - 2019 - Global synthesis of conservation studies reveals the importance of small habitat patches for biodiversity.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Jongman, Rob H.G.</author><author>Külvik, Mart</author><author>Kristiansen, Ib</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>European ecological networks and greenways</title><secondary-title>Landscape and Urban Planning</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Landscape and Urban Planning</full-title></periodical><pages>305-319</pages><volume>68</volume><issue>2-3</issue><keywords><keyword>Ecological network</keyword><keyword>Environmental planning</keyword><keyword>Europe</keyword><keyword>Greenway</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2004</year></dates><isbn>0169-2046</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/S0169-2046(03)00163-4</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Jongman et al, 2004.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>In the context of European integration, networks are becoming increasingly important in both social and ecological sense. Since the beginning of the 1990s, societal and scientific exchanges are being restructured as the conceptual approaches towards new nature conservation strategies have been renewed. Within the framework of nature conservation, the notion of an ecological network has become increasingly important. Throughout Europe, regional and national approaches are in different phases of development, which are all based on recent landscape ecological principles. Ecological networks are interpreted in a variety of ways depending on different historical roots of nature conservation, planning and scientific traditions, different geographical and administrative levels, different land uses, and in the end the political decision-making is dependent on actors with different land use interests. This complex interaction between cultural and natural features results in quite different ways for the elaboration of ecological networks and greenways. © 2003 Elsevier B.V. All rights reserved.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Mahlum, Shad</author><author>Cote, David</author><author>Wiersma, Yolanda F</author><author>Kehler, Dan</author><author>Clarke, Keith D</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Evaluating the Barrier Assessment Technique Derived from FishXing Software and the Upstream Movement of Brook Trout through Road Culverts</title><secondary-title>Transactions of the American Fisheries Society</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Transactions of the American Fisheries Society</full-title></periodical><pages>39-48</pages><volume>143</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2014</year></dates><publisher>Taylor &amp; Francis</publisher><electronic-resource-num>10.1080/00028487.2013.825641</electronic-resource-num><notes>doi: 10.1080/00028487.2013.825641

FISHXing produces conservative estimates of brown trout movement as studied through Pit tagging</notes><research-notes>doi: 10.1080/00028487.2013.825641

FISHXing produces conservative estimates of brown trout movement as studied through Pit tagging</research-notes><urls><web-urls><url>https://doi.org/10.1080/00028487.2013.825641</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Starr, Scott M.</author><author>Benstead, Jonathan P.</author><author>Sponseller, Ryan A.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Spatial and temporal organization of macroinvertebrate assemblages in a lowland floodplain ecosystem</title><secondary-title>Landscape Ecology</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Landscape Ecology</full-title></periodical><pages>1017-1031</pages><volume>29</volume><issue>6</issue><keywords><keyword>Connectivity</keyword><keyword>Flood pulse</keyword><keyword>Floodplain</keyword><keyword>Invertebrate communities</keyword><keyword>Spatiotemporal</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2014</year></dates><isbn>1098001400</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1007/s10980-014-0037-8</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Starr et al. 2014.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>An important goal in ecology is to understand controls on community structure in spatially and temporally heterogeneous landscapes, a challenge for which riverine floodplains provide ideal laboratories. We evaluated how spatial position, local habitat features, and seasonal flooding interact to shape aquatic invertebrate community composition in an unregulated riverine floodplain in western Alabama (USA). We quantified sediment invertebrate assemblages and habitat variables at 23 sites over a 15-month period. Dissolved oxygen (DO) varied seasonally and among habitats, with sites less connected to the river channel experiencing frequent hypoxia (2 mg O2 L-1) at the sediment-water interface. Differences in water temperature among sites were lowest (1°C) during winter floodplain inundation, but increased to &gt;14°C during spring and summer as sites became isolated. Overall, local habitat conditions were more important in explaining patterns in assemblage structure than was spatial position in the floodplain (e.g., distance to the main river channel). DO was an important predictor of taxonomic richness among sites, which was highest where hydrologic connections to the main river channel were strongest. Compositional heterogeneity across the floodplain was lowest immediately following inundation and increased as individual sites became hydrologically isolated. Our results illustrate how geomorphic structure and seasonal flooding interact to shape floodplain aquatic assemblages. The flood pulse of lowland rivers influences biodiversity through effects of connectivity on hydrologic flushing in different floodplain habitats, which may prevent the development of harsh environmental conditions that exclude certain taxa. Such interactions highlight the ongoing consequences of river regulation for taxonomically diverse floodplain ecosystems.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><titles><title>Connecting Gola Rainforest</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><dates><year>2018</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://09ThomasStarnes.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Url, Stable</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Spatiotemporal dynamics of prairie wetland networks : power-law scaling and implications for conservation planning Author ( s ): Christopher K . Wright Spatiotemporal of prairie wetland networks : dynamics and implications for conservation scaling plannin</title></titles><periodical/><pages>1924-1930</pages><volume>91</volume><issue>7</issue><keywords><keyword>and range shifts</keyword><keyword>law scaling</keyword><keyword>more</keyword><keyword>prairie pothole region</keyword><keyword>wetlands</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2013</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Wright, 2010.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Clobert, J. and M. Baguette</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Dispersal Ecology and J ean C lobert M ichel B aguette</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Dispersal Ecology and Evolution.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Of, Report</author><author>Network, Ecological</author><author>Norfolk, Project F O R</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>REPORT OF ECOLOGICAL NETWORK MAPPING PRESENTATION OF METHODOLOGY AND DRAFT MAPS FOR CONSULTATION R . Land Norfolk Wildlife Trust For Norfolk Biodiversity Partnership</title><secondary-title>Methodology</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Methodology</full-title></periodical><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Ecological network mapping project 2006.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Crawford, T</author><author>Gosden, J D</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>River and canal structures</title><secondary-title>Fluvial Design Guide</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Fluvial Design Guide</full-title></periodical><pages>1-36</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2009</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Crawford, Gosden - 2009 - River and canal structures.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>WTR</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>The Wildlife Trusts</title><secondary-title>Wayfaring tree</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Wayfaring tree</full-title></periodical><keywords/><dates><year>2014</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://The Wildlife Trusts and ecological habitat mapping.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.wildlifetrusts.org/species/wayfaring-tree</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Keith, Alexandre</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>for Nature Tomorrow</title><secondary-title>English</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>English</full-title></periodical><pages>1990 - 2001</pages><issue>575</issue><keywords><keyword>Planning for biodiversity</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2001</year></dates><isbn>0967-876X</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.futures.2008.07.021</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://r687_part_1[1] (1).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>A list of all the invertebrates known to be dependent on decaying wood in Britain and Ireland. The species names are annotated with basic information on the known ecology and distribution. The British list currently approaches 1800 species while the Irish list contains just over 600 species. The listing is intended to be a starting point for further analysis of this important fauna</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Baxter, R.</author><author>Hastings, N.</author><author>Law, a.</author><author>Glass, E. J..</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>[ No Title ]</title><secondary-title>Animal Genetics</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Animal Genetics</full-title></periodical><pages>561-563</pages><volume>39</volume><issue>5</issue><keywords><keyword>1999</keyword><keyword>also</keyword><keyword>antigen</keyword><keyword>bola</keyword><keyword>bola-drb3</keyword><keyword>bovine</keyword><keyword>called the bovine leucocyte</keyword><keyword>complex</keyword><keyword>genotyping</keyword><keyword>includes many immune-related genes</keyword><keyword>lewin et al</keyword><keyword>mhc</keyword><keyword>of cattle</keyword><keyword>the major histocompatibility complex</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2008</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Bourne et al. 2011.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Acreman, M.</author><author>Holden, J.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>How wetlands affect floods</title><secondary-title>Wetlands</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Wetlands</full-title></periodical><pages>773-786</pages><volume>33</volume><issue>5</issue><keywords><keyword>Floods</keyword><keyword>Hydrology</keyword><keyword>Peat</keyword><keyword>Runoff generation</keyword><keyword>Water storage</keyword><keyword>Water table</keyword><keyword>Wetlands</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2013</year></dates><isbn>0277-5212</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1007/s13157-013-0473-2</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Acreman and Holden, 2013.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>It is widely recognised that wetlands play an important role in the hydrological cycle, influencing groundwater recharge, low flows, evaporation and floods. This has led to policies being formulated world-wide to conserve and manage wetlands to deliver these key services, especially flood risk reduction. Generic statements have often been published about wetland hydrological services but the term “wetlands” covers many land types, including wet woodlands, reedbeds, peat bogs, fens, and salt marshes. Each of these wetland types can have a hydrological function that is subtly different, making it difficult to generalise the flood reduction services of wetlands. In this paper we focus on two example wetland types (upland rain-fed wetlands and floodplain wetlands) to demonstrate why there are differences in flood functions both within and between wetland types. Upland wetlands generally tend to be flood generating areas while floodplain wetlands have a greater potential to reduce floods. However, landscape location and configuration, soil characteristics, topography, soil moisture status and management all influence whether these wetlands provide flood reduction services.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>LOWE, WINSOR H.</author><author>LIKENS, GENE E.</author><author>POWER, MARY E.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Linking Scales in Stream Ecology</title><secondary-title>BioScience</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>BioScience</full-title></periodical><pages>591</pages><volume>56</volume><issue>7</issue><keywords><keyword>dispersal</keyword><keyword>networks</keyword><keyword>resiliency</keyword><keyword>rivers</keyword><keyword>streams</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2006</year></dates><isbn>0006-3568</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1641/0006-3568(2006)56[591:LSISE]2.0.CO;2</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Lowe et al(b), 2006.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://academic.oup.com/bioscience/article/56/7/591-597/234350</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The hierarchical structure of natural systems can be useful in designing ecological studies that are informative at multiple spatial scales. Although stream systems have long been recognized as having a hierarchical spatial structure, there is a need for more empirical research that exploits this structure to generate an understanding of population biology, community ecology, and species–ecosystem linkages across spatial scales. We review studies that link pattern and process across multiple scales of stream-habitat organization, highlighting the insight derived from this multiscale approach and the role that mechanistic hypotheses play in its successful application. We also describe a frontier in stream research that relies on this multiscale approach: assessing the consequences and mechanisms of ecological processes occurring at the network scale. Broader use of this approach will advance many goals in applied stream ecology, including the design of reserves to protect stream biodiversity and the conservation of freshwater resources and services.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Legall, Nathaniel</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>This certificate indicates that has completed a course in : Outdoor First Aid 2 Days</title></titles><periodical/><pages>4330731</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2016</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Wild Talent - Outdoor First Aid 2 Days - 25.01.16-26.01.16_007.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Generic">31</ref-type><titles><title>Condatis1.0LaunchProgramme_latest.pdf</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Unknown - Unknown - Condatis1.0LaunchProgramme_latest.pdf.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Ieep, Marianne Kettunen</author><author>Iucn, Andrew Terry</author><author>Tucker, Graham</author><author>Solutions, Ecological</author><author>Ieep, Andrew Jones</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Kettunen, M, Terry, A., Tucker, G. &amp; Jones A. 2007. Guidance on the maintenance of landscape features of major importance for wild flora and faun (1).pdf</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><dates><year>2007</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://adaptation_fragmentation_guidelines.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Camargo, R P</author><author>Bueno, C C</author><author>Deda, D K</author><author>Leite, F De Lima</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>4.1 Introduction</title></titles><periodical/><pages>93-120</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2017</year></dates><isbn>978-0-19-513890-0</isbn><accession-num>24603084</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/B978-0-323-49780-0/00004-1</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Camargo et al. - 2017 - 4.1 Introduction.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Hodgson, Jenny A.</author><author>Wallis, David W.</author><author>Krishna, Ritesh</author><author>Cornell, Stephen J.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>How to manipulate landscapes to improve the potential for range expansion</title><secondary-title>Methods in Ecology and Evolution</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Methods in Ecology and Evolution</full-title></periodical><pages>1558-1566</pages><volume>7</volume><issue>12</issue><keywords><keyword>circuit theory</keyword><keyword>climate change</keyword><keyword>dispersal</keyword><keyword>ecological restoration</keyword><keyword>indicators</keyword><keyword>invasion</keyword><keyword>networks</keyword><keyword>optimisation</keyword><keyword>reserve design</keyword><keyword>systematic conservation planning</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><isbn>2041-210X</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1111/2041-210X.12614</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Hodgson et al. - 2016 - How to manipulate landscapes to improve the potential for range expansion(2).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>1. Climate change is a global threat to species, and their capacity to adapt could be limited by habitat fragmentation. Many initiatives to restore habitats, increase connectivity and/or ensure `functioning ecological networks' are explicitly or implicitly trying to address this threat. However, existing methods of analysing networks mainly treat the landscape as static, and it is difficult to use these to plan restoration. 2. We use a recent method to approximate the speed of a species' range expansion through a landscape by an analogy to an electrical circuit, which takes into account both the rates of colonisation between patches and the rates at which occupied habitat produces new emigrants. Based on this, we propose and test two methods that can help to optimise the spatial arrangement of habitat for range expansion. 3. First, high current flowing through a habitat patch indicates that it should be a priority for conservation, and this can be the basis of an algorithm for iteratively dropping the least valuable patches. Secondly, high power in a link between two patches indicates that it is a bottleneck in the circuit, and this can be the basis of an algorithm for iteratively adding new patches in the most efficient places. We show that these methods perform well for a variety of realistic landscape patterns, assuming known and fixed dispersal ability and source/target locations. 4. The calculations involved for each parameter set are fast enough to be used as building blocks in a larger optimisation for practical planning of landscapes for multiple species. Thus, we lay the foundation for a new genre of systematic conservation planning, which efficiently proposes restoration as well as minimising loss.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wiens, John A</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Riverine landscapes: taking landscape ecology into the water - WIENS - 2002 - Freshwater Biology - Wiley Online Library</title></titles><periodical/><pages>501-515</pages><keywords><keyword>ecological flows</keyword><keyword>landscape ecology</keyword><keyword>river ecosystems</keyword><keyword>scale</keyword><keyword>spatial pattern</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2002</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Wiens - 2002 - Riverine landscapes taking landscape ecology into the water - WIENS - 2002 - Freshwater Biology - Wiley Online Library.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1046/j.1365-2427.2002.00887.x/full</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Fish, Freshwater</author><author>Munksgaard, Blackwell</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>CO</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><dates><year>2003</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Laffaille-EFF-2003.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>De Meyer, J.</author><author>Christiaens, J.</author><author>Adriaens, D.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Diet-induced phenotypic plasticity in European eel (Anguilla anguilla)</title><secondary-title>Journal of Experimental Biology</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Journal of Experimental Biology</full-title></periodical><pages>354-363</pages><volume>219</volume><issue>3</issue><keywords><keyword>dimorphism</keyword><keyword>elver eel stage</keyword><keyword>trophic plasticity</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><isbn>1477-91450022-0949</isbn><accession-num>26847560</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1242/jeb.131714</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://De Meyer, Christiaens, Adriaens - 2016 - Diet-induced phenotypic plasticity in European eel (Anguilla anguilla).pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://jeb.biologists.org/cgi/doi/10.1242/jeb.131714</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Two phenotypes are present within the European eel population: broad-heads and narrow-heads. The expression of these phenotypes has been linked to several factors, such as diet and differential growth. The exact factors causing this dimorphism, however, are still unknown. In this study, we performed a feeding experiment on glass eels from the moment they start to feed. Eels were either fed a hard diet, which required biting and spinning behavior, or a soft diet, which required suction feeding. We found that the hard feeders develop a broader head and a larger adductor mandibulae region than eels that were fed a soft diet, implying that the hard feeders are capable of larger bite forces. Next to this, soft feeders develop a sharper and narrower head, which could reduce hydrodynamic drag, allowing more rapid strikes towards their prey. Both phenotypes were found in a control group, which were given a combination of both diets. These phenotypes were, however, not as extreme as the hard or the soft feeding group, indicating that some specimens are more likely to consume hard prey and others soft prey, but that they do not selectively eat one of both diets. In conclusion, we found that diet is a major factor influencing head shape in European eel and this ability to specialize in feeding on hard or soft prey could decrease intra-specific competition in European eel populations.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><titles><title>Creating and Ecological Network</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://ecological-networks-1.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Gido, Keith B.</author><author>Whitney, James E.</author><author>Perkin, Joshuah S.</author><author>Turner, Thomas F.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Fragmentation, connectivity and fish species persistence in freshwater ecosystems</title><secondary-title>Conservation of Freshwater Fishes</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Conservation of Freshwater Fishes</full-title></periodical><pages>292-323</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2015</year></dates><isbn>9781139627085</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1017/CBO9781139627085.011</electronic-resource-num><notes>See appendix for good figures on relationship between number of barriers and fish diversity</notes><research-notes>See appendix for good figures on relationship between number of barriers and fish diversity</research-notes><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Gido et al., 2016.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://www.cambridge.org/core/product/identifier/CBO9781139627085A096/type/book_part</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>&lt;div class=&quot;abstract&quot; data-abstract-type=&quot;normal&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class='bold'&gt;OVERVIEW&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fragmentation poses one of the greatest threats to freshwater fish biodiversity (Nilsson &lt;span class='italic'&gt;et al&lt;/span&gt;., 2005; Reidy-Liermann &lt;span class='italic'&gt;et al&lt;/span&gt;., 2012). Whereas damming of large rivers is perhaps the most obvious form of fragmentation (e.g., Nilsson &lt;span class='italic'&gt;et al&lt;/span&gt;., 2005), smaller, semipermeable barriers such as road crossings (Perkin &amp; Gido, 2012) or water withdrawals that dry sections of a river network (Falke &lt;span class='italic'&gt;et al&lt;/span&gt;., 2011) also pose a conservation challenge. In glacial regions, lakes that are naturally connected through waterways are increasingly being isolated by summer evaporation and groundwater loss (Baki &lt;span class='italic'&gt;et al&lt;/span&gt;., 2012). Climate and land-use changes also isolate populations in headwater reaches by increasing temperatures (Rahel &lt;span class='italic'&gt;et al&lt;/span&gt;., 1996) or drying of streams (Falke &lt;span class='italic'&gt;et al&lt;/span&gt;., 2011) in downstream reaches. Finally, barriers can form when the occurrence of a species, such as a large predator, inhibits the movement of prey through a dispersal corridor (Fraser &lt;span class='italic'&gt;et al&lt;/span&gt;., 1995). This severing of connectivity in aquatic habitats affects species persistence through multiple stressors (Chapters 4 and 6) including limiting dispersal necessary to fulfil important life stages, exacerbating negative species interactions, and inhibiting recolonisation following disturbance. Barriers to movement isolate small populations leading to reduced genetic diversity (Chapter 16) and potentially compromise long-term population persistence (e.g. Wofford &lt;span class='italic'&gt;et al&lt;/span&gt;., 2005).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this chapter, we discuss how fragmentation disrupts dispersal and migration of freshwater fishes and the long-term consequences for population diversity and stability. We begin with a global overview of the problem followed by a review of theoretical and empirical methods for quantifying the effects of fragmentation on population viability. We conclude with a discussion of conservation challenges along with future research and management recommendations. The primary tenet of our review is that persistence of species in fragmented systems is dependent on the nature of barriers to dispersal and ecological traits of species, particularly their ability to complete critical life-history stages within fragmented habitats (Figure 10.1). We often refer to the terms fragmentation, isolation and connectivity. Whereas there are instances where these might be used interchangeably, we consider fragmentation to represent habitats that have been partitioned into smaller habitats and by extension result in smaller populations. The terms connectivity and isolation refer to the ability or lack of ability, respectively, of fishes to disperse into or out of particular habitats.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Charles, S.</author><author>Bravo De La Parra, R.</author><author>Mallet, J. P.</author><author>Persat, H.</author><author>Auger, P.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Annual spawning migrations in modelling brown trout population dynamics inside an arborescent river network</title><secondary-title>Ecological Modelling</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Ecological Modelling</full-title></periodical><pages>15-31</pages><volume>133</volume><issue>1-2</issue><keywords><keyword>Aggregation techniques</keyword><keyword>Arborescent river network</keyword><keyword>Leslie matrix</keyword><keyword>Population dynamics</keyword><keyword>Salmo trutta</keyword><keyword>Spawning migrations</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2000</year></dates><isbn>0304-3800</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/S0304-3800(00)00277-5</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Charles et al., 2000.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>In the present paper, the annual spawning migration of adults is introduced into a model, describing the Salmo trutta population dynamics in a hierarchically organized river network (four levels and 15 interconnected patches) model based on previous work. The model describes simultaneously demographic and migration processes taking place at different time scales: migrations of individuals between patches at a fast time scale (e.g. the week or the month), the annual spawning migration of adults and the demography at the slow time scale of the year. The S. trutta population is sub-divided into three age-classes (young of the year, juveniles, and adults). We used a Leslie-type model, coupled with a migration matrix associated with the annual spawning process, and a second migration matrix associated with fast movements of individuals between patches throughout the year. All demographic and migratory parameters are constant, leading to a linear model governing 45 state variables (15 patches x three age-classes). By taking advantage of the two time scales and using aggregation techniques for the case of discrete time models, the complete model was approximated by a reduced one, with only three global variables (one per age-class) evolving at the slow time scale. Demographic indices were calculated for the population, and a sensibility analysis was performed to detect which parameters influence the most model predictions. We also quantified how modifications of the river network structure, by channels (change in connections between patches) or dams (patch deletion), influence the global population dynamics. We checked that the strategy of annual spawning migrations is actually beneficial for the population (the asymptotic population growth rate is increased), and that dams may have a more detrimental effect on the whole population dynamics than channelling. (C) 2000 Elsevier Science B.V.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Book">1</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Bennett, Graham</author><author>Mulongoy, Kalemani J.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Review of experience with ecological networks, corridors and buffer zones</title><secondary-title>Secretariat of the Convention on Biological Diversity, Montreal, Technical Series No. 23</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Secretariat of the Convention on Biological Diversity, Montreal, Technical Series No. 23</full-title></periodical><pages>100 pp</pages><keywords/><dates><year>2006</year></dates><isbn>9292250426</isbn><accession-num>12917927</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.immuni.2010.08.011</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://CBD - Review of experience with ecological networks....pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>The unprecedented increase in the human use of natural resources over the last century has adversely affected ecosystems, leading to their fragmentation and loss of biological diversity. Protected areas that remain as isolated units, surrounded by a radically altered habitat, almost always face serious viability problems over the long term. The importance of strengthening ecological coherence and resilience as necessary condi- tions for both biodiversity conservation and sustainable development has been echoed in conservation and development fora for some time. One of the actions identifi ed by the Plan of Implementation of the World Summit on Sustainable Development as necessary to achieve the 2010 biodiversity target is to “promote the development of national and regional ecological networks and corridors”. The CBD programme of work on protected areas emphasizes the importance of establishing protected areas in a mosaic of land and water habitats to facilitate maintenance of ecological processes. Goal 1.2 of the programme of work specifi cally calls for in- tegrating protected areas into broader land- and seascapes and sectors to maintain the structural and functional viability of ecosystems. Specifi c activities of the programme of work refer to “linking habitats”, such as buffer zones around protected areas (where human use is allowed to the extent that it does not undermine the integ- rity of protected areas), biological corridors and ecological stepping stones. The concept of the ecological network becomes important here. Ecological networks provide an operational model for conserving biological diversity while reconciling the confl ict- ing demand of natural resource use. Ecological networks connect ecosystems and populations of species that are threatened by fragmented habi- tats, facilitating genetic exchange between differ- ent populations and thus increasing the chances of survival of threatened species. The ecological network concept also provides a tool for ecologi- cal design and physical planning that facilitates interaction with other types of land use. A large number of ecological networks have been developed around the world. However, a thorough and systematic compilation of infor- mation on ecological networks and their contri- bution to conservation and the sustainable use of biological diversity and sustainable develop- ment was, until now, not available. Against this background, the Secretariat of the Convention on Biological Diversity has undertaken this ini- tiative. This review document contains detailed information on the development and implemen- tation of ecological networks in each of the fi ve UN regions. The examples and case studies pro- vide a wealth of information on ecological net- works. The study also focuses on lessons learned and on the suitability of ecological networks for biodiversity conservation, sustainable use and poverty alleviation, and on their contribution to the 2010 target. I hope this review will provide a better understanding of ecological networks and as- sist protected-area managers and policy-makers in governments, NGOs and communities to develop ecological networks when planning and implementing protected areas and to achieve the twin objectives of biodiversity conservation and sustainable development. I thank the authors for undertaking such an exhaustive review and presenting the informa- tion clearly and succinctly. I am also grateful to the Government of Netherlands for providing fi nancial resources.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><titles><title>No Title</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><dates><year>2017</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://2017_Sleight_Nathan_Thesis_FINAL.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Generic">31</ref-type><titles><title>#.pdf</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://#.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Wilkinson, J W</author><author>Starnes, T</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Ten years of Jersey Toadwatch: Analysis &amp; recommendations</title></titles><periodical/><pages>1-31</pages><volume>16/01</volume><keywords/><dates><year>2016</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://R Jersey Toadwatch Report 20161114 DM.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://www.gov.je/SiteCollectionDocuments/Government and administration/R Jersey Toadwatch Report 20161114 DM.pdf</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Report">10</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Kirn, Rich</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>The Vermont Culvert Aquatic Organism Passage Screening Tool</title></titles><periodical/><pages>120</pages><issue>March</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2009</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://rv_VTAOPScreeningTool.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><titles><title>Somerset ’ s Ecological Network</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><dates><year>2015</year></dates><notes>Delphi process (iterrative series of questionnatires) used to determine permeability scores with the help of experts</notes><research-notes>Delphi process (iterrative series of questionnatires) used to determine permeability scores with the help of experts</research-notes><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Unknown - 2015 - Somerset ’ s Ecological Network.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Swt, Version</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Version 2-SWT 2017 Use in Somerset Only</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><dates><year>2017</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Swt - 2017 - Version 2-SWT 2017 Use in Somerset Only.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Buddendorf, Willem B.</author><author>Jackson, Faye L.</author><author>Malcolm, Iain A.</author><author>Millidine, Karen J.</author><author>Geris, Josie</author><author>Wilkinson, Mark E.</author><author>Soulsby, Chris</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Integration of juvenile habitat quality and river connectivity models to understand and prioritise the management of barriers for Atlantic salmon populations across spatial scales</title><secondary-title>Science of The Total Environment</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Science of The Total Environment</full-title></periodical><issue>November</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2018</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.scitotenv.2018.11.263</electronic-resource-num><notes>Barrier prioritisation is sensitive to habitat weighting: not accounting for habitat quality can lead to over- or underestimating the importance of IMBs. 

Rationale for combining FIPEX with BEETLE</notes><research-notes>Barrier prioritisation is sensitive to habitat weighting: not accounting for habitat quality can lead to over- or underestimating the importance of IMBs. 

Rationale for combining FIPEX with BEETLE</research-notes><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Buddendorf et al. - 2018 - Integration of juvenile habitat quality and river connectivity models to understand and prioritise the man(2).pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>https://linkinghub.elsevier.com/retrieve/pii/S0048969718346199</url></web-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Piper, Adam T.</author><author>Wright, Rosalind M.</author><author>Walker, Alan M.</author><author>Kemp, Paul S.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Escapement, route choice, barrier passage and entrainment of seaward migrating European eel, Anguilla anguilla, within a highly regulated lowland river</title><secondary-title>Ecological Engineering</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Ecological Engineering</full-title></periodical><pages>88-96</pages><volume>57</volume><issue>0</issue><keywords><keyword>Barrier</keyword><keyword>Fish migration</keyword><keyword>Fish passage</keyword><keyword>Habitat fragmentation</keyword><keyword>Telemetry</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2013</year></dates><isbn>0925-8574</isbn><accession-num>26136454</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.ecoleng.2013.04.030</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Piper et al. - 2013 - Escapement, route choice, barrier passage and entrainment of seaward migrating European eel, Anguilla anguilla, wi.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Fluvial disconnectivity can have important impacts on fish populations, including hindering movement between habitats required for different ontogenic stages. Recruitment of the European eel (Anguilla anguilla) has reduced by over 90% since the early 1980's, in part due to the effect of riverine barriers on its catadromous migration. There is a legislative requirement to restore free passage, increase habitat availability, and limit anthropogenic losses at intakes to aid eel recovery and good ecological status; necessitating an improved understanding of underlying processes. Escapement, route choice, delay at structures, and entrainment at water abstraction points of downstream migrating silver eels were examined using acoustic and Passive Integrated Transponder (PIT) telemetry in the heavily regulated lower river Stour, UK. Downstream migrating adult eel (n=. 69) were trapped approximately 10. km upstream of the tidal limit, surgically implanted with an acoustic transducer and PIT transponder, and released between October and December in 2009 and 2010. Movements of tagged individuals were monitored by a linear array of 19 fixed acoustic receivers extending from the release site, through the last 9.2. km of the freshwater catchment. Three groups of water control structures, two water abstraction intakes and several possible routes of migration are present in the reach. Seventy six and 65% of tagged eels escaped from the study reach in 2009 and 2010, respectively. Entrainment at a single intake was the principal cause of loss and positively related to rapid increases in abstraction whilst eels were in the vicinity of the intake. Route choice into the estuary was dependent on discharge over a large intertidal weir; opening regimes of a tidal gate at the termination of the alternative channel; and abstraction rate at a nearby water intake. Long delays (up to 68.5 days) and recurrent behaviour were associated with several structures in the study reach; high variability between individuals reflected the management of spill at weirs. Potential scenarios for minimising entrainment and delay through integrated management of water level control structures and abstraction rates are discussed. © 2013 Elsevier B.V.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><titles><title>Field manual level A assessment</title></titles><periodical/><volume>111</volume><keywords/><notes>Where did you first see this?

'Whilst it is useful to note the category of the obstacle and attempt to categorise to a sub-division, it is not as important in terms of the actual functional challenges that an obstacle presents to fish passage.'

Structure type does not denote passability as much as flow over structure, angle, esc.

Required data by section of form

Section 2
- Construction material

Section 3
- Water depth
- Water Velocity at crests of water structures (0.6 depth &amp;amp; streambed)

Section 4

- Vertical height
- Structure length
- The gradient
- Levels of turbulence
- Structure dimensions (Culvert gap width, mesh gap size)
- Screening present

What is DS and US on the recording form? Downstream and upstream

Adult eel (AE) row doesn't account for movement upstream and can't assess movement around the system. 

No barrier is considered present if water depth is more than 0.008m (height of eel when flat?) - too simplified?

Downstream Permeability scores (0.3 = little permeability/ 0.6 / 1.0 = no permeability)


Bund - 0.3
Culvert - 1.0
Flap valve - 0.3
Outlet - 0.6
Penstock - 0.3
Screen - 0.6
Siphon - 0.3
Spillway - 0.3
Stoplogs - 0.6
Tilting Weir - 1.0
Valve (inlet) - 0.6
Weir - 0.6

Upstream Permeability scores (0.3 / 0.6 / 1.0)


Bund - 0.3
Culvert - 1.0
Flap valve - 0.3
Outlet - 0.6
Penstock - 0.3
Screen - 0.3
Siphon - 0.3
Spillway - 1.0
Stoplogs - 0.3
Tilting Weir - 0.6
Valve (inlet) - 0.6
Weir - 0.6</notes><research-notes>Where did you first see this?

'Whilst it is useful to note the category of the obstacle and attempt to categorise to a sub-division, it is not as important in terms of the actual functional challenges that an obstacle presents to fish passage.'

Structure type does not denote passability as much as flow over structure, angle, esc.

Required data by section of form

Section 2
- Construction material

Section 3
- Water depth
- Water Velocity at crests of water structures (0.6 depth &amp;amp; streambed)

Section 4

- Vertical height
- Structure length
- The gradient
- Levels of turbulence
- Structure dimensions (Culvert gap width, mesh gap size)
- Screening present

What is DS and US on the recording form? Downstream and upstream

Adult eel (AE) row doesn't account for movement upstream and can't assess movement around the system. 

No barrier is considered present if water depth is more than 0.008m (height of eel when flat?) - too simplified?

Downstream Permeability scores (0.3 = little permeability/ 0.6 / 1.0 = no permeability)


Bund - 0.3
Culvert - 1.0
Flap valve - 0.3
Outlet - 0.6
Penstock - 0.3
Screen - 0.6
Siphon - 0.3
Spillway - 0.3
Stoplogs - 0.6
Tilting Weir - 1.0
Valve (inlet) - 0.6
Weir - 0.6

Upstream Permeability scores (0.3 / 0.6 / 1.0)


Bund - 0.3
Culvert - 1.0
Flap valve - 0.3
Outlet - 0.6
Penstock - 0.3
Screen - 0.3
Siphon - 0.3
Spillway - 1.0
Stoplogs - 0.3
Tilting Weir - 0.6
Valve (inlet) - 0.6
Weir - 0.6</research-notes><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://WFD111_Phase_2a_Fish_obstacles_manual.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Cote, David</author><author>Kehler, Dan G.</author><author>Bourne, Christina</author><author>Wiersma, Yolanda F.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A new measure of longitudinal connectivity for stream networks</title><secondary-title>Landscape Ecology</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Landscape Ecology</full-title></periodical><pages>101-113</pages><volume>24</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>Aquatic connectivity</keyword><keyword>Barriers</keyword><keyword>Connectivity indices</keyword><keyword>Dendritic ecological networks</keyword><keyword>Fish passage</keyword><keyword>Fragmentation</keyword><keyword>River networks</keyword><keyword>Watersheds</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2009</year></dates><isbn>0921-2973</isbn><accession-num>7774</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1007/s10980-008-9283-y</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Cote et al. - 2009 - A new measure of longitudinal connectivity for stream networks.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Abstract Habitat connectivity is a central factor in shaping aquatic biological communities, but few tools exist to describe and quantify this attribute at a network scale in riverine systems. Here, we develop a new index to quantify longitudinal connectivity of river networks based on the expected probability of an organism being able to move freely between two random points of the network. We apply this index to two fish life histories and evaluate the effects of the number, passability, and placement of barriers on river network connectivity through the use of simulated dendritic ecological networks. We then extend the index to a real world dendritic river system in Newfoundland, Canada. Our results indicate that connectivity in river systems, as represented by our index, is most impacted by the first few barriers added to the system. This is in contrast to terrestrial systems, which are more resilient to low levels of connectivity. The results show a curvilinear relationship between barrier passability and structural connectivity. This suggests that an incremental improvement in passability would result in a greater improvement to river network connectivity for more permeable barriers than for less permeable barriers. Our analysis of the index in simulated and real river networks also showed that barrier placement played an important role in connectivity. Not surprisingly, barriers located near the river mouth have the greatest impact on fish with diadromous life histories while those located near the center of the river network have the most impact on fish with potadromous life histories. The proposed index is conceptually simple and sufficiently flexible to deal with variations in river structure and biological communities. The index will enable researchers to account for connectivity in habitat studies and will also allow resource managers to characterize watersheds, assess cumulative impacts of multiple barriers and determine priorities for restoration.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Mahlum, Shad</author><author>Kehler, Dan</author><author>Cote, David</author><author>Wiersma, Yolanda F.</author><author>Stanfield, Les</author><author>Rosenfeld, Jordan</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Assessing the biological relevance of aquatic connectivity to stream fish communities</title><secondary-title>Canadian Journal of Fisheries and Aquatic Sciences</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Canadian Journal of Fisheries and Aquatic Sciences</full-title></periodical><pages>1852-1863</pages><volume>71</volume><issue>12</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2014</year></dates><isbn>0706-652X</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1139/cjfas-2013-0646</electronic-resource-num><notes>Where you first read about FIPEX</notes><research-notes>Where you first read about FIPEX</research-notes><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Mahlum et al. - 2014 - Assessing the biological relevance of aquatic connectivity to stream fish communities.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://www.nrcresearchpress.com/doi/abs/10.1139/cjfas-2013-0646</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>Recent advances in the ability to quantify longitudinal connectivity of riverine systems is enabling a better under- standing of how connectivity affects fish assemblages. However, the role of connectivity relative to other factors, such as land use, in structuring biological assemblages is just emerging. We assessed the relevance of a structural connectivity index to stream fish communities at a relatively large scale (across five watersheds of Lake Ontario) while controlling for confounding habitat variables, such as land use, elevation, and stream topology. The results were assessed to determine whether species’ sensitivities to connectivity are in accordance with expectations of life history. Our results indicated that at large scales, structural connectivity explains significant amounts of variation in community structure (1% to 5.4% as measured by Bray–Curtis similarity), but remains secondary to other habitat components. Connectivity also was significantly related to abundance in three of the seven species assessed. The lower explanatory power of our models compared with studies done at smaller scales suggests that the relevance of connectivity to fish communities is scale-dependent and diminishes relative to other environ- mental factors at larger spatial extents.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Shaw, Edward A.</author><author>Lange, Eckart</author><author>Shucksmith, James D.</author><author>Lerner, David N.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Importance of partial barriers and temporal variation in flow when modelling connectivity in fragmented river systems</title><secondary-title>Ecological Engineering</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Ecological Engineering</full-title></periodical><pages>515-528</pages><volume>91</volume><keywords><keyword>Aquatic connectivity</keyword><keyword>Barriers</keyword><keyword>Dendritic ecological networks</keyword><keyword>Fish passage</keyword><keyword>Fishway</keyword><keyword>Habitat fragmentation</keyword><keyword>River networks</keyword><keyword>Weirs</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2016</year></dates><publisher>Elsevier B.V.</publisher><isbn>0925-8574</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.ecoleng.2016.01.030</electronic-resource-num><notes>Temporal considerations when modelling ecological networks.

pg. 519 Upstream and downstream 'symmetry' cannot be assumed. It's a lot easier to fall of a pile of hay than to jump ontop of one</notes><research-notes>Temporal considerations when modelling ecological networks.

pg. 519 Upstream and downstream 'symmetry' cannot be assumed. It's a lot easier to fall of a pile of hay than to jump ontop of one</research-notes><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Shaw et al., 2016.pdf</url></pdf-urls><web-urls><url>http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.ecoleng.2016.01.030</url></web-urls></urls><abstract>The potential for catchment-scale connectivity modelling to help plan the restoration of connectivity in fragmented river systems is not yet well understood. In the present study the importance of two interrelated aspects of such modelling in determining predictions of connectivity are explored: (1) uncertainty in the passability of partial barriers (such as fish passes) and how the passabilities of series of partial barriers combine, and (2) temporal variation in connectivity due to flow. Connectivity for Atlantic salmon (Salmo salar L.) and European perch (Perca fluviatilis L.) are modelled under alternative restoration strategies in the heavily impounded Don Catchment UK using two different methods for simulating the combined passability of series of partial barriers. Catchment-scale hydraulic and connectivity modelling were integrated using a novel method to account for the effect of flow on connectivity, achieved by consideration of flow-fish pass efficiency relationships and the treatment of gaps between habitat patches as partial barrier. Modelled connectivity is very sensitive to uncertainty in barrier passability and the method used to simulate the combined passability of series of partial barriers. Flow also has a strong and complex effect on connectivity, with predicted temporal patterns being particularly dependent on how the combined impact of series of barriers is modelled. The sensitivity of the modelling constrains its capacity to predict the outcome of alternative connectivity restoration strategies. Nevertheless it does serve as a tool to think critically about connectivity restoration. If applied thoughtfully in full awareness of its limitations it can still be used assist in the planning and appraisal of alternative restoration options. The modelling also provides a number of important practical insights. It shows that series of fish passes may be ineffective unless they operate at very high efficiencies. Small changes to flow-fish pass efficiency relationships can have a large effect on temporal patterns in connectivity. Overall fish pass efficiency is comprised of attraction and passage efficiencies which may differ in the extent to which they are determined by random processes. This likely has significant implications for the nature of the combined passability of series of fish passes.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Buddendorf, Willem B.</author><author>Jackson, Faye L.</author><author>Malcolm, Iain A.</author><author>Millidine, Karen J.</author><author>Geris, Josie</author><author>Wilkinson, Mark E.</author><author>Soulsby, Chris</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Integration of juvenile habitat quality and river connectivity models to understand and prioritise the management of barriers for Atlantic salmon populations across spatial scales</title><secondary-title>Science of The Total Environment</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Science of The Total Environment</full-title></periodical><keywords/><dates><year>2018</year></dates><electronic-resource-num>10.1016/j.scitotenv.2018.11.263</electronic-resource-num><notes>Scottish obstacles to fish migration. How was the dataset created.

Created in the 80s by staff from Marine Scotland Science using information provided by District Salmon Fishery Boards, Fisheries Trusts and local angling clubs.</notes><research-notes>Scottish obstacles to fish migration. How was the dataset created.

Created in the 80s by staff from Marine Scotland Science using information provided by District Salmon Fishery Boards, Fisheries Trusts and local angling clubs.</research-notes><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Buddendorf et al. - 2018 - Integration of juvenile habitat quality and river connectivity models to understand and prioritise the manage.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>South, Area</author><author>Quay, Victoria</author><author>Hughes, Jonathan</author><author>Smith, Aedán</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Please return this form to : npfteam@scotland.gsi.gov.uk or NPF Team , The Scottish Please return this form to : npfteam@scotland.gsi.gov.uk or NPF Team , The Scottish Government , Area 2H South , Victoria Quay , Leith , Edinburgh , EH6 6QQ</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Scottish Wildlife Trust National Ecological Network proposal.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Manual, User</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>FishXing</title></titles><periodical/><issue>February</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2006</year></dates><notes>Only designed for culverts

Pg. 108 for desciption of percent passage/barrierity/passability calculation 

Query input for FishXing?
See pg. 17
o Culvert Shape 
o Dimensions (diameter, rise, span) 
o Material and Corrugation 
o Installation (At Grade or Embedded) 
o Culvert Length 
o Culvert Slope (Can be automaticlally calculated if inlet and outlet bottom elevations are known) 
o Culvert Outlet Bottom Elevation 
o Entrance Loss

Culvert info. pg 28</notes><research-notes>Only designed for culverts

Pg. 108 for desciption of percent passage/barrierity/passability calculation 

Query input for FishXing?
See pg. 17
o Culvert Shape 
o Dimensions (diameter, rise, span) 
o Material and Corrugation 
o Installation (At Grade or Embedded) 
o Culvert Length 
o Culvert Slope (Can be automaticlally calculated if inlet and outlet bottom elevations are known) 
o Culvert Outlet Bottom Elevation 
o Entrance Loss

Culvert info. pg 28</research-notes><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Manual - 2006 - FishXing.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Id, W B</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>SNIFFER WFD111_Phase_2a_Field_recording_sheets</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://WFD111_Phase_2a_Field_recording_sheets.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Service, Forest</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>National inventory and assessment procedure</title><secondary-title>Development</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Development</full-title></periodical><keywords/><dates><year>2005</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Service - 2005 - National inventory and assessment procedure.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>The U.S. Department of Agriculture (USDA) prohibits discrimination in all its programs and activities on the basis of race, color, national origin, age, disability, and where applicable, sex, marital status, familial status, parental status, religion, sexual orientation, genetic information, political beliefs, reprisal, or because all or part of an individual's income is derived from any public assistance program. (Not all prohibited bases apply to all programs.) Persons with dis-abilities who require alternative means for communication of program information (Braille, large print, audiotape, etc.) should contact USDA's TARGET Center at (202) 720–2600 (voice and TDD).</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Lane, Martineau</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>If you need this document in large print , audio , Braille , alternative format or in a different language , please contact the Biodiversity Co-ordinator on 01603-222112 and we will do our best to help .</title><secondary-title>October</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>October</full-title></periodical><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Making Space for Nature and People.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>England, Natural</author><author>Chapter, See</author><author>Chapter, See</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Identifying spatial priorities for Ecological Networks Chapter 4 A guide to map-based models and tools for planning ecological networks</title></titles><periodical/><keywords/><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://England, Chapter, Chapter - Unknown - Identifying spatial priorities for Ecological Networks Chapter 4 A guide to map-based models and t.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>European, Thames</author><author>Project, Eel</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>The Thames European Eel Project Report , 2017</title></titles><periodical/><pages>1-22</pages><issue>December</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2017</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://ZSL_2017_EelProjectReport_Final.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Cote, David</author><author>Kehler, Dan G.</author><author>Bourne, Christina</author><author>Wiersma, Yolanda F.</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>A new measure of longitudinal connectivity for stream networks</title><secondary-title>Landscape Ecology</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Landscape Ecology</full-title></periodical><pages>101-113</pages><volume>24</volume><issue>1</issue><keywords><keyword>Aquatic connectivity</keyword><keyword>Barriers</keyword><keyword>Connectivity indices</keyword><keyword>Dendritic ecological networks</keyword><keyword>Fish passage</keyword><keyword>Fragmentation</keyword><keyword>River networks</keyword><keyword>Watersheds</keyword></keywords><dates><year>2009</year></dates><isbn>0921-2973</isbn><accession-num>7774</accession-num><electronic-resource-num>10.1007/s10980-008-9283-y</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Cote et al. - 2009 - A new measure of longitudinal connectivity for stream networks(2).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>Abstract Habitat connectivity is a central factor in shaping aquatic biological communities, but few tools exist to describe and quantify this attribute at a network scale in riverine systems. Here, we develop a new index to quantify longitudinal connectivity of river networks based on the expected probability of an organism being able to move freely between two random points of the network. We apply this index to two fish life histories and evaluate the effects of the number, passability, and placement of barriers on river network connectivity through the use of simulated dendritic ecological networks. We then extend the index to a real world dendritic river system in Newfoundland, Canada. Our results indicate that connectivity in river systems, as represented by our index, is most impacted by the first few barriers added to the system. This is in contrast to terrestrial systems, which are more resilient to low levels of connectivity. The results show a curvilinear relationship between barrier passability and structural connectivity. This suggests that an incremental improvement in passability would result in a greater improvement to river network connectivity for more permeable barriers than for less permeable barriers. Our analysis of the index in simulated and real river networks also showed that barrier placement played an important role in connectivity. Not surprisingly, barriers located near the river mouth have the greatest impact on fish with diadromous life histories while those located near the center of the river network have the most impact on fish with potadromous life histories. The proposed index is conceptually simple and sufficiently flexible to deal with variations in river structure and biological communities. The index will enable researchers to account for connectivity in habitat studies and will also allow resource managers to characterize watersheds, assess cumulative impacts of multiple barriers and determine priorities for restoration.</abstract></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Brue, Upper</author><author>Boards, Drainage</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>South Drain Water Level Management Plan Lower Brue Drainage Board and Upper Brue Drainage Board Approved April 2010 Contents</title></titles><periodical/><pages>1-53</pages><issue>April</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2010</year></dates><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Brue, Boards - 2010 - South Drain Water Level Management Plan Lower Brue Drainage Board and Upper Brue Drainage Board Approved April (2).pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls></record><record><database name="mycollection.enl" path="mycollection.enl">mycollection.enl</database><ref-type name="Journal Article">0</ref-type><contributors><authors><author>Convertino, Matteo</author><author>Rigon, Riccardo</author><author>Maritan, Amos</author><author>Rodriguez-Iturbe, Ignacio</author><author>Rinaldo, Andrea</author></authors></contributors><titles><title>Probabilistic structure of the distance between tributaries of given size in river networks</title><secondary-title>Water Resources Research</secondary-title></titles><periodical><full-title>Water Resources Research</full-title></periodical><pages>1-16</pages><volume>43</volume><issue>11</issue><keywords/><dates><year>2007</year></dates><isbn>0043-1397</isbn><electronic-resource-num>10.1029/2007WR006176</electronic-resource-num><urls><pdf-urls><url>internal-pdf://Convertino et al. - 2007 - Probabilistic structure of the distance between tributaries of given size in river networks.pdf</url></pdf-urls></urls><abstract>We analyze the distribution of the distances between tributaries of a given size (or of sizes larger than a given area) draining along either an open boundary or the mainstream of a river network. By proposing a description of the distance separating prescribed merging contributing areas, we also address related variables, like mean (or bankfull) flow rates and channel and riparian area widths, which are derived under a set of reasonable hydrologic assumptions. The importance of such distributions lies in their ecological, hydrologic, and geomorphic implications on the spreading of species along the ecological corridor defined by the river network and on the propagation of infections due to water-borne diseases, particularly in view of exact theoretical predictions explicitly using the alongstream distribution of confluences carrying a given flow. Use is made here of real river networks, suitably extracted from digital elevation models, optimal channel networks, and exactly solved tree-like constructs like the Peano and the Scheidegger networks. The results obtained redefine theoretically in a coherent and general manner and verify observationally the distribution function of the above distances and thus provide the general probabilistic structure of tributaries in river networks. Specifically, we find that the probability of exceedence of the alongstream distance d of tributaries of size larger than a has the explicit form P(&gt;= d) = exp (-Cd/a(H/(1+ H))), where C is a constant that depends on the choice of boundary conditions and H &lt;= 1 is the Hurst exponent.</abstract></record></records></xml>
